<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Use Cases on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/usecase/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Use Cases on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/usecase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data</title>
      <link>/usecase/big_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 19:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/big_data/</guid>
      <description> Big Data
Google Trends YouTube Geolocational data   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Impact Assessment of Music Industry</title>
      <link>/usecase/impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 19:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/impact/</guid>
      <description>Economic Impact Assessment
Economic Impact Assessment</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying Remuneration</title>
      <link>/usecase/pcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/pcr/</guid>
      <description>Private Copying Remuneration
PCR PCR PCR</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Access and Participation surveys</title>
      <link>/usecase/cap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/cap/</guid>
      <description>Cultural Access and Participation Surveys are standardized surveys designed to measure various market-based and non-market based (amateur, liturgical, etc.) cultural activities, including concerts, streaming subscriptions, singing, etc. They are based on various quantative sociological models and had been standardized by the Eurostat working group ESSNet-Culture.
The CEEMID CAP surveys are usually live interviews that allow cross-country comparison, and they are used both for market forcasting, market analytics, royalty and compensation value setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Professionals surveys</title>
      <link>/usecase/musicians/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/musicians/</guid>
      <description>The three income streams model is essentially a value chain based model that was developed in the United Statesand adopted by the European Commission’s Joint Research Center for European CCI policy purposes. We made minor adaptations in the three income model for applicability in Central Europe.
While in the original American model sound recordings are the “main” income stream, currently, especially in Central Europe the live performance stream earns the most income for a typical musician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royalty Setting</title>
      <link>/usecase/royalty_setting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/royalty_setting/</guid>
      <description>The copyright and neighboring right royalty is the wage-like earning of the music performer, the composer and producer. In popular music performers usually play their own composition and sing their own lyrics. If the musician is self-published, all the three royalties directly pay the artist’s work. If a professional publisher is helping the artist as a composer, or a record producer as a recorded performer, they usually share the respective royalty revenues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>