<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Use Cases on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/usecase/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Use Cases on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/usecase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Export</title>
      <link>/usecase/music_export/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/music_export/</guid>
      <description>Music export is complicated to define, because music has a live and recorded element. In recorded music, the author, the performer and the producer are eligible for copyright and neighboring right royalties. In live music, the author and the performer are eligible for revenues, and they may or may not have a different nationality, and the concert promoter and booking manager may earn profits in another country.
Finding out the domestic country for the author, the performer and the producer may be a very difficult task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-use Public Sector Information</title>
      <link>/usecase/psi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 19:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/psi/</guid>
      <description>I have been involved in the regulatory work and application building on re-use of public sector information. The European governments, and the EU itself, collects information that is worth billions of euros for the commercial and non-governmental sector.
While PSI is generally free, or very cheap in the EU, the re-use of these information sources usually requires deep knowledge and further investment, given that these public information sources were never designed for the secondary public or commercial need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data</title>
      <link>/usecase/big_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 19:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/big_data/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID was made out of necessity in EU member states when official statistics are missing key elements of the music or other creative industries. We had been experimenting with big data sources since 2017, especially to find ways to break down statistics to regional or city level, and to find leading indictors or estimators where government statistics are not available, or available only with a very long time delay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Impact Assessment of Music Industry</title>
      <link>/usecase/impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 19:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/impact/</guid>
      <description>Economic impact assessments, such as multiplier calculations, direct, indirect and induced employment-, tax-, value added effects calculations are very often needed for larger grants, or the design of grant calls; illegal state aid must be avoided, for example, when designing film tax shelters; or considering various policy options.
Such calculations require in the background very large amount of highly structure statistical data, which is very difficult to obtain and work with for non-specialist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying Remuneration</title>
      <link>/usecase/pcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/pcr/</guid>
      <description>Private Copying Remuneration
PCR PCR PCR</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Access and Participation surveys</title>
      <link>/usecase/cap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/cap/</guid>
      <description>Cultural Access and Participation Surveys are standardized surveys designed to measure various market-based and non-market based (amateur, liturgical, etc.) cultural activities, including concerts, streaming subscriptions, singing, etc. They are based on various quantative sociological models and had been standardized by the Eurostat working group ESSNet-Culture.
The CEEMID CAP surveys are usually live interviews that allow cross-country comparison, and they are used both for market forecasting, market analytics, royalty and compensation value setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Professionals surveys</title>
      <link>/usecase/musicians/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/musicians/</guid>
      <description>The three income streams model is essentially a value chain based model that was developed in the United States and adopted by the European Commission’s Joint Research Center for European CCI policy purposes pdf download. We made minor adaptations in the three income model for applicability in Central Europe.
While in the original American model sound recordings are the “main” income stream, currently, especially in Central Europe the live performance stream earns the most income for a typical musician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royalty Setting</title>
      <link>/usecase/royalty_setting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/royalty_setting/</guid>
      <description>The copyright and neighboring right royalty is the wage-like earning of the music performer, the composer and producer. In popular music performers usually play their own composition and sing their own lyrics. If the musician is self-published, all the three royalties directly pay the artist’s work. If a professional publisher is helping the artist as a composer, or a record producer as a recorded performer, they usually share the respective royalty revenues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>