<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grants on Antal Dániel, CFA</title>
    <link>/hu/tags/grants/</link>
    <description>Recent content in grants on Antal Dániel, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>hu</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 10:16:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/hu/tags/grants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Közös analitikai eszközök építése: jobb turnétervezés, belföldi és nemzetközi promóció</title>
      <link>/hu/talk/2019_11_15_bush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 10:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/talk/2019_11_15_bush/</guid>
      <description>I am going to look back on the needs assessment of Hungarian music professionals in 2015 and Czechs in 2019.I will also compare the problems of the Hungarian scene in 2015, 2019 with the current issues in Czechia, Slovakia and Austria.
I would like to provide an opportunity on BUSH to give personal feedback to the artists and professionals who gave their personal details in our annual CEEMID Music Professional Survey from Hungary, or anywhere else in the region if they make it to BUSH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comperative Study On The Music Markets of the CEE Region</title>
      <link>/hu/talk/2019_11_08_nouvelle_prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 10:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/talk/2019_11_08_nouvelle_prague/</guid>
      <description>I am going to present the Czech results from our regional Central European Music Industry Report, and the first version of a comprehensive, national music development program that we started to work on in the organization of SoundCzech with 25 music professionals representing more than 20 stakeholders in the How We Would Like To Work in the Czech Music Industry in 2020 ex ante evaluation workshop.
I would like to provide an opportunity on Nouvelle Prague to give personal feedback to the artists and professionals who gave their personal details in our annual CEEMID Music Professional Survey from Czechia, or anywhere else in the region if they make it to Nouvelle Prague.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>