<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Antal Dániel, CFA</title>
    <link>/hu/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Antal Dániel, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>hu</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/hu/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Budapest Showcase Hub &amp; Conference 2019</title>
      <link>/hu/post/2019-11-18-bush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/2019-11-18-bush/</guid>
      <description>We had a very interesting discussion day on the Budapest Showcase Hub with the regional independent labels in the workshop hosted by HAIL and with some concert promoters and music educators in the main conference program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My economic impact package, iotables, has a much updated released on CRAN</title>
      <link>/hu/post/iotables_04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/iotables_04/</guid>
      <description>The analytical functions of the package create the usual economic impact analysis, including direct effects, multipliers on gross value added, employment, CO2 or other factors. The package creates a programmatic interface to compare economic impact changes in time, or compare any country with any country in the European Union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eurpoean Comparison: How Many People Ever Pay For Music, Film or Software</title>
      <link>/hu/post/how_many_ever_pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/how_many_ever_pay/</guid>
      <description>In Europe, there is a big difference between the use of electronic entertainment devices in richer and poorer countries. Nevertheless, the real difference is between the number of people who sometimes and who never pay for downloaded music, films and software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovak Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/hu/post/ceemid_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/ceemid_19/</guid>
      <description>We presented the most important findings of the Slovak Music Industry Report with the project sponsor, Mgr. Tomas Miks, member of SOZA’s management team in the first SHARPE music conference in Bratislava.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovak Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/hu/post/sharpe_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/sharpe_18/</guid>
      <description>We presented the most important findings of the Slovak Music Industry Report with the project sponsor, Mgr. Tomas Miks, member of SOZA’s management team in the first SHARPE music conference in Bratislava.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEE Mini Recording Industry Workshop</title>
      <link>/hu/post/cee_mini_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/cee_mini_17/</guid>
      <description>A Baltikumtól a Balkánig tartó zenei piacképemet prezentáltam kiváló kollégáknak a State51 budapesti workshopján, amelyen a WIN és az IFPI vezetői is részt vettek. Élénk vita alakult ki a résztvevőkkel arról, hogy a feltörekvő piacok miért olyan lassan törekszenek a fejlett piacok után a digitális zenei életben.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMP Session: Licensing, How To Tackle The Value Gap And A Discussion on Licensing Initiatives</title>
      <link>/hu/post/ceempc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/ceempc/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID had the honor to participate in the third panel of CEEMP in Warsaw together with Ben McEwen from ICE; Jules Parker from Spotify and Dominic Houston from Netflix, and Chris Butler from Music Sales, who is also the chairperson of ICMP. Our panel was moderated by Nigel Elderton from peermusic, who is also the new chairperson of PRS in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Croatian Music Industry</title>
      <link>/hu/post/makk15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/makk15/</guid>
      <description>Daniel Antal presented the preliminary findings of the Croatian music industry research in the International Authors’ and Creators’ Conference in Zagreb on 24 November 2015. The presentation was largely based on analysis of various CEEMID databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first national Hungarian Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/hu/post/proart_report_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/proart_report_15/</guid>
      <description>The report was compiled with joining data and knowledge from collective management agencies for composer, producer and performer royalties, and market leading companies Sziget (organizer of Sziget festival and many more festivals), WMMD music distribution company, market-leading Schubert Music Publishing and A38, Hungary’s leading music club, together with producer and audience survey data, tax authority data and other government sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications for tariff setting</title>
      <link>/hu/post/cisac_goodg_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/cisac_goodg_13/</guid>
      <description>My short presentation highlighted the fact that the CEE region’s is much richer in terms of household cultural and recreational spending than music publishers believe.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>