<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music-export on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/music-export/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music-export on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/music-export/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Exports &amp; Imports</title>
      <link>/project/music-export/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/music-export/</guid>
      <description>Europe, like most regions of the world, is a net importer of music, but has very signficant export potential. Intra-European export is also very significant, especially from Germany, France, Sweden and the Netherlands.
The Central and Eastern European region is relatively weak in exporting recorded and live performances, but it is among global leaders in creating export revenues from festivals.
Currently I am involved in creating predicitve models that help finding the best potential foreign market for music, and I make economic impact assessments of cultural tourism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Market Shares on Spotify Hitlists</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</guid>
      <description>If we take a look at the streaming charts of the region, we usually find that the vast majority of the streamed songs are foreign songs - except for Austria, U.S. songs. For comparison, we added a similar, middle-income emerging market (Argentina) and a rich, small-population English-speaking country, Australia to the chart. These countries seem to be in a similar position to the CEE countries.
Arguably, the strongest countries of songwriting are the United States and Brazil - these are the countries that have ran out of the ISRC recording identifier range.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>