<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music-industry on Antal Dániel, CFA</title>
    <link>/hu/tags/music-industry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music-industry on Antal Dániel, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>hu</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/hu/tags/music-industry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Közép- és keleteurópai zeneipari jelentés 2020</title>
      <link>/hu/publication/ceereport_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/publication/ceereport_2020/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID és a Consolidated Independent bemutatta és az európai érdekeltekkel megvitatta az első Közép- és kelet-európai Zeneipari jelentést, mint a nemzeti (magyar, szlovák, cseh) és nemzetközi összehasonlító, tényalapú kulturális- és kreatívipari közpolitika alkotás egy esettanulmányát. Az eseménynek az Európai Bizottság és a Geothe Intézet társszervezésében megrendezett CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference adott helyszínt.
A kutatási eredményeinket korábban bemutattuk és megvitattuk a regionális érintettekkel Bécsben, Prágában, Budapesten és Pozsonyban.
A vontakozó korábbi prezentációk a blog szekcióban találhatók meg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budapest Showcase Hub &amp; Conference 2019</title>
      <link>/hu/post/2019-11-18-bush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/2019-11-18-bush/</guid>
      <description>A HAIL szervezésében egy nagyon hasznos workshopon vettem részt a Budapest Showcase Hub konferencián.  Másnap koncertszervezőkkel és oktatókkal beszélgettünk az előadásom kapcsán.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digitáils zeneipar éves szeminárium</title>
      <link>/hu/talk/2019_11_19_mokk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 10:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/talk/2019_11_19_mokk/</guid>
      <description>Olvasnivalók:
Antal Dániel, 2015. “A Proart zeneipari jelentése. [The Music Industry Report of Proart].” ProArt Szövetség a Szerzői Jogokért Egyesület. http://zeneipar.info/letoltes/proart-zeneipari-jelentes-2015.pdf.
Az Európai Parlament és a Tanács (EU) 2019/790 irányelve (2019. április 17.) a digitális egységes piacon a szerzői és szomszédos jogokról, valamint a 96/9/EK és a 2001/29/EK irányelv módosításáról. 2019. Official Journal of the European Union. https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/HU/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32019L0790.
EYGM. 2014. “Creating Growth – Measuring Cultural and Creative Industries in Europe.” EYGM Limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Szlovák zeneipari jelentés</title>
      <link>/hu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/</guid>
      <description>Az egész jelentés ingyenesen letölthető a SOZA honlapjáról.
Sajtóbeszámolók:
Magyarul: Új Szó: Tudományosan a hazai zeneiparról
Szlovákul:
SME: SOZA predstavila prvú Správu o slovenskom hudobnom priemysle
Kreatívna Europa: Historicky prvá Správa o slovenskom hudobnom priemysle prináša okrem analýz aj odporúčania pre budúcnosť</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eurpoean Comparison: How Many People Ever Pay For Music, Film or Software</title>
      <link>/hu/post/how_many_ever_pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/how_many_ever_pay/</guid>
      <description>In Europe, there is a big difference between the use of electronic entertainment devices in richer and poorer countries. Nevertheless, the real difference is between the number of people who sometimes and who never pay for downloaded music, films and software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovak Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/hu/post/ceemid_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/ceemid_19/</guid>
      <description>We presented the most important findings of the Slovak Music Industry Report with the project sponsor, Mgr. Tomas Miks, member of SOZA’s management team in the first SHARPE music conference in Bratislava.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovak Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/hu/post/sharpe_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/sharpe_18/</guid>
      <description>We presented the most important findings of the Slovak Music Industry Report with the project sponsor, Mgr. Tomas Miks, member of SOZA’s management team in the first SHARPE music conference in Bratislava.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEE Mini Recording Industry Workshop</title>
      <link>/hu/post/cee_mini_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/cee_mini_17/</guid>
      <description>A Baltikumtól a Balkánig tartó zenei piacképemet prezentáltam kiváló kollégáknak a State51 budapesti workshopján, amelyen a WIN és az IFPI vezetői is részt vettek. Élénk vita alakult ki a résztvevőkkel arról, hogy a feltörekvő piacok miért olyan lassan törekszenek a fejlett piacok után a digitális zenei életben.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Growth of the Hungarian Popular Music Repertoire: Who Creates It And How Does It Find An Audience</title>
      <link>/hu/publication/made_in_hungary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/publication/made_in_hungary/</guid>
      <description>Being visible in the world is always difficult in the Central and Eastern European region. Made in Hungary is the first book in the Popular Music Studies series of Routledge from the region. A description of our first datasets, the motivation of the research and the CEEMID concept is laid out as a closing, quantitative chapter in the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Croatian Music Industry</title>
      <link>/hu/post/makk15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/post/makk15/</guid>
      <description>Daniel Antal presented the preliminary findings of the Croatian music industry research in the International Authors’ and Creators’ Conference in Zagreb on 24 November 2015. The presentation was largely based on analysis of various CEEMID databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hungarian Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/hu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>