<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>surveys on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/surveys/</link>
    <description>Recent content in surveys on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/surveys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMID</title>
      <link>/project/ceemid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ceemid/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID (Central and Eastern European Music Industry Databases) was created out of necessity following a CISAC Good Governance Seminar for European Societies in 2013. The adoption of European single market and copyright rules, and the increased activity of competition authority and regulators required a more structured approach to set collective royalty and compensations tariffs in the region.
In 2014 three societies, Artisjus, HDS and SOZA realized that need to make further efforts to modernize the way they measure their own economic impact, the economic value of their licenses to remain competitive in advocating the interests vis-&amp;#224;-vis domestic governments, international organizations like CISAC and GESAC and the European Union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Musician Career Paths</title>
      <link>/post/career_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/career_path/</guid>
      <description>In the 20th century the first career step was to get on stage and create a credible live performance. After several years on the stage musician’s got a recording contract, and usually even later they registered their first composition. The recording stream was the most important revenue source. The making of a record was expensive and offered considerable royalties or advances.
In the 21st century the live music stream is far more important than the recordings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>