<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>market-report on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/market-report/</link>
    <description>Recent content in market-report on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/market-report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Eurpoean Comparison: How Many People Ever Pay For Music, Film or Software</title>
      <link>/post/how_many_ever_pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how_many_ever_pay/</guid>
      <description>In our recent private copying reports we compiled European survey data relevant to analysis. In Europe, there is a big difference between the use of electronic entertainment devices in richer and poorer countries. Nevertheless, the real difference is between the number of people who sometimes and who never pay for downloaded music, films and software.
In some countries of Europe, less then 10 percent of the population ever pays for the content that is loaded to their computers, smartphones and tablets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovak Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/post/sharpe_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sharpe_18/</guid>
      <description>You can review the slides here.
           </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMP Session: Licensing, How To Tackle The Value Gap And A Discussion on Licensing Initiatives</title>
      <link>/post/ceemp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ceemp/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID had the honor to participate in the third panel of CEEMP in Warsaw together with Ben McEwen from ICE; Jules Parker from Spotify and Dominic Houston from Netflix, and Chris Butler from Music Sales, who is also the chairperson of ICMP. Our panel was moderated by Nigel Elderton from peermusic, who is also the new chairperson of PRS in the UK.
Jules from Spotify spoke about their new initiative, Spotify for Publishers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Reports</title>
      <link>/project/market_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/market_report/</guid>
      <description>I have been creating market reports for 20 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opportunities for branch lines in the new European regulatory environment</title>
      <link>/publication/hu_branch_lines_2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hu_branch_lines_2004/</guid>
      <description>Original title in Hungarian: A mellékvonalak lehetőségei az új európai vasútszabályozási környezetben, in: Közlekedéstudományi Szemle</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the first year of the liberalized rail freight market for re-regulation</title>
      <link>/publication/hu_rail_transport_2004-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hu_rail_transport_2004-copy/</guid>
      <description>Original title in Hungarian: A vasúti áruszállítási piac első évének tanulságai az újraszabályozás szempontjából.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the first year of the liberalized rail freight market for re-regulation</title>
      <link>/publication/hu_rail_transport_2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hu_rail_transport_2004/</guid>
      <description>Original title in Hungarian: A vasúti áruszállítási piac első évének tanulságai az újraszabályozás szempontjából.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>