<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Antal Dániel, CFA</title>
    <link>/hu/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Antal Dániel, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>hu</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/hu/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Független kiadók kihívásai 2020-ban</title>
      <link>/hu/talk/2019_11_14_hail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 10:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/talk/2019_11_14_hail/</guid>
      <description>A Magyaországra és a Balkánra vonatkozó adatokat fogom kiemelni a Central European Music Industry Report piacelemzésből, és a digitális csatornákon való terjesztés illetve a DSM Irányelv átültetésével kapcsolatos néhány aktuális témáról fogunk beszélgetni. Szóba fog kerülni egy, a balkáni zeneipar feltérképezését és fejlesztését célzó projekt is a helyi partnerekkel.
Egyúttal alkalmat szeretnék teremetni arra, hogy személyes visszajelzéseket adjak azoknak a zeneipari szakembereknek, akik megadták a személyes adataikat a CEEMID zeneipari szakemberek felmérése 2019 felmérésben.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Közös analitikai eszközök építése: jobb turnétervezés, belföldi és nemzetközi promóció</title>
      <link>/hu/talk/2019_11_15_bush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 10:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/talk/2019_11_15_bush/</guid>
      <description>I am going to look back on the needs assessment of Hungarian music professionals in 2015 and Czechs in 2019.I will also compare the problems of the Hungarian scene in 2015, 2019 with the current issues in Czechia, Slovakia and Austria.
I would like to provide an opportunity on BUSH to give personal feedback to the artists and professionals who gave their personal details in our annual CEEMID Music Professional Survey from Hungary, or anywhere else in the region if they make it to BUSH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comperative Study On The Music Markets of the CEE Region</title>
      <link>/hu/talk/2019_11_08_nouvelle_prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 10:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/talk/2019_11_08_nouvelle_prague/</guid>
      <description>I am going to present the Czech results from our regional Central European Music Industry Report, and the first version of a comprehensive, national music development program that we started to work on in the organization of SoundCzech with 25 music professionals representing more than 20 stakeholders in the How We Would Like To Work in the Czech Music Industry in 2020 ex ante evaluation workshop.
I would like to provide an opportunity on Nouvelle Prague to give personal feedback to the artists and professionals who gave their personal details in our annual CEEMID Music Professional Survey from Czechia, or anywhere else in the region if they make it to Nouvelle Prague.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panelbeszélgetés az első Közép-európai Zeneipari Jelentésről</title>
      <link>/hu/talk/waves_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/talk/waves_2019/</guid>
      <description>A panelbeszélgetés az első közép-európai jelentés (Ausztria, Bulgária, Csehország, Horvátország, Észtország, Lengyelország, Litvánia, Magyarország, Örményország, Románia, Szerbia, Szlovákia, Szlovénia) Waves Music Showcase Fesztviál és Konferencia keretében.
Az alábbiak a konferencia programjában szerepelnek, amit fordítás nélkül teszek közzé.
CEEMID – Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Databases was created out of necessity: many Central and Eastern European countries are lacking effective cross-industry or governmental statistics on music or on cultural industries in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Szlovák Zeneipari Jelentés 2019 bemutatója</title>
      <link>/hu/talk/slovak_report19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/talk/slovak_report19/</guid>
      <description>The venue is V klub, Národné Osvetové Centrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMPC session: Licensing, How To Tackle The Value Gap And A Discussion On Licensing Initiatives</title>
      <link>/hu/talk/ceempc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/talk/ceempc/</guid>
      <description>More information in the blogpost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAKK2015 International authors’ and creators’ conference</title>
      <link>/hu/talk/makk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/talk/makk/</guid>
      <description>Click on the **Slides** button above to view the built-in slides feature.  Slides can be added in a few ways:
 Create slides using Academic&amp;rsquo;s Slides feature and link using url_slides parameter in the front matter of the talk file Upload an existing slide deck to static/ and link using url_slides parameter in the front matter of the talk file Embed your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using shortcodes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>