<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Antal, CFA on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Daniel Antal, CFA on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 18:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Musicians’ Living Standards And Life Satisfaction In The CEE Region</title>
      <link>/post/life_sat_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/life_sat_19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to get a high-level comparison among the living standards of musicians, we use the standard survey question used in Eurobarometer surveys for decades: how often have had the respondent difficulties with paying bills in the past year?   This is a very good starting point because it makes comparable the rough material standards of musicians and other professional groups in the EU, irrespective of local earnings and living costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Musicians everywhere, including rich countries like Germany, Austria and Slovenia have more problems with paying their bills than the general population in their countries.  The only seemingly different country is Bulgaria, but in this case, the self-reported difference is small, and generally Bulgarian musicians and other Bulgarian people have similarly frequent difficulties with paying their bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working in an emerging economy is more stressful than in a mature economy – making ends is more difficult, risks are greater and usually rules change faster. No wonder that people generally report higher level of life satisfaction in countries where the living standards are also higher: average life satisfaction in a country is &lt;a href=&#34;https://ourworldindata.org/happiness-and-life-satisfaction&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;greatly influenced&lt;/a&gt; by national income and general health level, measured by life expectancy.  However, it is also recorded since the 1970s that after reaching a certain level of living standards, life satisfaction does not increase further with economic conditions. Other factors, such as vocation, work-life balance and political factors play a role, too. Working in an emerging economy is more stressful than in a mature economy – making ends is more difficult, risks are greater and usually rules change faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the emerging music business countries, it is very important to see that the musicians not only earn little money, but as freelancers their income is mainly based on live performances, peaking in the festival season and in December. This income is usually taxed at far higher rates in the CEE region than in Western Europe or in non-creative industries.  Royalties, which should balance variable live performance earnings are far lower both as a percentage of total musician income and in euro terms than in advanced markets. This is often coupled with higher taxation, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid the bias of higher satisfaction levels in richer environments, we measure musician’s self-reported life satisfaction levels against the national averages from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dbk.gesis.org/dbksearch/sdesc2.asp?no=7489&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2018&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;11&lt;/sub&gt; Eurobarometer sample&lt;/a&gt;, scaled between the numerical values of -2 (not at all satisfied) to 2 (very satisfied).&lt;/p&gt;




  

&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/musician_charts/life_satisfaction_levels.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Comparing the life satisfaction levels of musicians with the general public, 2018-2019.&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our comparison shows that in most of our surveyed countries, musicians are more satisfied with their lives than the average person, despite having more material difficulties.  Of course, age, and other factors can contribute to this, but a vocational calling is certainly an important aspect, too.  The exceptions are, interestingly, Austria and Slovenia, where the general population has a very high level of life satisfaction, and where both musicians and the general public are generally more satisfied with their lives than in the other countries. In these cases, compared to the general population, music professional are less satisfied with their lives. In Serbia our sample is too small to draw real conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;




  

&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/musician_charts/difficulty_bills_levels.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Comparing the difficulties of paying bills among musicians and the general public, 2018-2019.&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Career in music can lead to higher life satisfaction than other similarly paid jobs in Europe.  However, music market stakeholders should focus on increasing the level of music professional earnings and reducing its variance within the year and over the years, because the material living conditions of musicians is significantly worse than the conditions of the general population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can read a lot more about this research &lt;a href=&#34;http://survey2019.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSM Directive, Value Gap &amp; Private Copying Levies</title>
      <link>/post/dsm_pcr_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dsm_pcr_19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Private copying after 60 years remains a very important way of spreading recorded music, books and audiovisual works, and a very important source of revenue for artists, composers, writers, film writers and performers if managed properly.   According to our research, the value of private copying is far bigger these days than when most CEE private copying remuneration mechanisms were set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/dir/2019/790/oj&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DSM Directive&lt;/a&gt; is not addressing these issues, it is aiming to re-arrange the power balance between users and rightsholders of certain unlicensed, or not fully-licensed and compensated uses. We see &lt;strong&gt;common threats and common opportunities&lt;/strong&gt; with the national implementations of the European legislation.  Especially in the CEE region, many harware manufacturers who enjoy the benefits of the earlier regime will lobby their governments to dampen the affects of the directive. Worse still, as it will re-open the national copyright legislation in all EU countries, there will be renewed pressure from hardware manufacturers, telecom companies and Pirate Parties to minimalize the private copying remuneration. Google/YouTube/Alphabet is likely to place previously unseen, coordinated pressure on each country to minimize the value transfer compensation and at the same time minimize or abolish private copying remuneration - in all EU capitals from Sofia to Paris, from Den Haag to Prague.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/dsm_pcr_19/gallery/conversion_to_payer.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Conversion over a decade: people start to pay online, but they are not everywhere turning for paid music and film sources.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/dsm_pcr_19/gallery/conversion_to_payer.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in many countries, no serious PCR regimes were created after the EU accession.  In these countries, according to our calculations, only 10-30% or even less of the equitable remuneration is collected due to legal constraints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the changes initiated by the &lt;em&gt;DSM Directive&lt;/em&gt; will be watered down, and equitable private copying remuneration will not be helped by new legislation, the music industries of these countries will conserve their huge gap compared to mature EU markets for further decades.  If they follow the lead of those countries that made significant progres in this field, they can make a big step to close that &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/cee_mini_17/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;gap&lt;/a&gt;.  This will require fact-based, rational, effective adovacy material that can convince the general public, the media, legislators, and when necessary, judges about the position of the music industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Export</title>
      <link>/usecase/music_export/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/music_export/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Music export is complicated to define, because music has a live and recorded element.  In recorded music, the author, the performer and the producer are eligible for copyright and neighboring right royalties.  In live music, the author and the performer are eligible for revenues, and they may or may not have a different nationality, and the concert promoter and booking manager may earn profits in another country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding out the domestic country for the author, the performer and the producer may be a very difficult task. While language is very important in most genres of popular music and in world music, language affiliation is usually a help only in small nation repertoires.  But the language of a song is so important that it may be the target variable of cultural policy tools such as radio or audiovisual quotas.
In classical and world music, the author may not be known or eligible for royalties anymore.  In popular music and some jazz, the author and performer are usually the same artists.  Nevertheless, the complexity remains. In contemporary classical music, jazz and some genres of popular music, language is not an issue because the music is instrumental, or the human voice has no real natural language connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;music-export-music-import&#34;&gt;Music Export &amp;amp; Music Import&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our view, music export and music import cannot be separated from each other.  Every single European market is a net importer of recorded music, given that there are no music markets where the domestic music market share exceeds 50%.  In live music, domestic music traditionally is market leader in all markets, but the concentration of ticket revenues in large arena concerts and the growth of festivals is threatening the positions of domestic live music.  The competition among songs, label and national repertoires is increasing very significantly with the rise of global streaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the recorded markets, radio and audiovisual quotas and an activist role of public broadcasters could maintain a 15-30 percent market share for local artists even in smaller markets. The rise of music streaming and SVOD streaming in audiovisual works makes many of these gatekeepers irrelevant unless they find their audience and role in the new streaming channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the live performances, some countries, especially Hungary, Serbia, Croatia and Poland found ways to create very significant export revenues for programming large festivals aimed at Western European audiences.  While these solutions create vital export revenues for the music ecosystem, i.e. for promoters and technicians, it creates less opportunity for local artists.  There is a growing pressure on domestic bands to extend their tour network abroad, given that the depth of domestic tour network is shrinking due to global and EU-wide small venue problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;artificial-intelligence-and-algorithms&#34;&gt;Artificial intelligence and algorithms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 21st century the total global repertoire of the last 60 years is in simultaneous competition with each other. Close to 100 million sound recordings are available in most markets.  In this global competition, most music is sold by AI algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-ceemid-intelligence-can-help&#34;&gt;How CEEMID intelligence can help?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Teach new algorithms that help defending the declining domestic markets, and recommend vibrant, new local music to local audiences, and connect them on live performances, too;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Extend market insight and tour scheduling for the whole European market, with cost, audience demography, audience taste, revenue forecast intelligence;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design quota schemes and public broadcaster strategies that maintain the public mandate in the 21st century;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design music grants that give the correct incentives to the right people.  Help both foreign market reach and domestic market cultivation with correct ex ante and ex post evaluations;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given the complexity of the concept of ‘music export’ in the context of cultural affiliation, language, artist residence, potential separation of composer, performer and producer, music export and import is a difficult topic that requires professional, fact-driven advocacy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMID Music Professionals Survey 2019</title>
      <link>/post/ceemid_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ceemid_19/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The fragmentation of the music business into microenterprises and freelance carriers make the work of a musician very complex.  Most musicians do not only fulfill the artistic role of a performer, composer, lyricist or composer.  In most cases, artists perform two artistic roles, but it is equally frequent that they perform a different, but still music related engineering, educator or managerial role.  Given that that average size of creative enterprises in Europe is less than two people, musicians are forced to do several very different things.  In the 20th century, larger companies, especially record labels had the necessary marketing, management, engineering staff to take care of this issues, but in the 21st century most musicians need to master all of these skills to a certain extent – at least to the extent that they can hire other, mainly freelance music professionals to help them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/three_income_streams_croatia.png&#34; alt=&#34;Three income streams model&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason why official labor statistics and economic statistics do not capture the performance of the music business well is that the classification of economic statistics dates to the 1960s.  Two key elements of a popular musician’s work, live performances and sound recordings are in different economic classes. Composer-performers, the typical musicians of popular music do not fit into this categorization.  Adding to this complexity the frequent presence of other artistic, technical, managerial or educational functions makes a musician’s work hard to categorize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The complexity of musician’s work makes professional training very challenging, too.  Popular music throughout the world is mainly learned in informal settings.  However, this is not the ideal setting to learn the necessary managerial, economic, legal and other skills that are necessary to fulfil the freelance job of a professional musician.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-three-income-stream-model-of-the-music-industry&#34;&gt;The Three Income Stream Model of the Music Industry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three income streams model is essentially a value chain based model that was developed in the United States and adopted by the European Commission’s Joint Research Center for European CCI policy purposes. We made minor adaptations in the three income model for applicability in less developed markets in Central and Eastern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in the original American model sound recordings are the “main” income stream, currently, especially in Central Europe the live performance stream earns the most income for a typical musician. The author’s stream is the oldest, traditionally and analytically first part of the music industry that includes revenue streams based on musical works exploited by music publishers and via author’s CMO societies such as SOZA. In the US it is called the publishing stream, but in Central Europe it is dominated by authors’ societies, so we modified the label.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IMPALA CEE Workshop 2019</title>
      <link>/talk/impala_cee_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/impala_cee_2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;///www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/vJJ9iJK0pA7io&#34; width=&#34;595&#34; height=&#34;485&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom:5px&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel/impala-cee-2019-workshop&#34; title=&#34;IMPALA CEE 2019 Workshop&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IMPALA CEE 2019 Workshop&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dániel Antal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Data &amp; Re-use Of Public Sector Information</title>
      <link>/usecase/psi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 19:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/psi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been involved since 2003 in the creation of official and non-official statistics and in the re-use of public sector information.  CEEMID from the onset took benefit from the re-use of public sector information directive which had been replaced in 2019 with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?qid=1561563110433&amp;amp;uri=CELEX:32019L1024&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EU Open Data Directive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The European governments, and the EU itself, collects information that is worth billions of euros for the commercial and non-governmental sector. While PSI is generally free, or very cheap in the EU, the re-use of these information sources usually requires deep knowledge and further investment, given that these public information sources were never designed for the secondary public or commercial need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CEEMID has built hundreds of indicators from various EU public information sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are creating new music and audiovisual industry related statistics from raw data collected for other purposes, such as inflation measurement or public policy assessment in the EU using our proprietary software and some open source software.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our economic impact assessment tool is, for example, builds heavily on our &lt;a href=&#34;http://iotables.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;iotables software&lt;/a&gt; that we released as an open source software within the framework of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ropengov.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rOpenGov&lt;/a&gt; collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data</title>
      <link>/usecase/big_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 19:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/big_data/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;CEEMID was made out of necessity in EU member states when official statistics are missing key elements of the music or other creative industries.  We had been experimenting with big data sources since 2017, especially to find ways to break down statistics to regional or city level, and to find leading indictors or estimators where government statistics are not available, or available only with a very long time delay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://webgate.ec.europa.eu/fpfis/mwikis/essnetbigdata/index.php/Main_Page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ESSnet Big Data&lt;/a&gt; is a project within the European statistical system (ESS) jointly undertaken by 28 partners. Its objective is the integration of big data in the regular production of official statistics, through pilots exploring the potential of selected big data sources, and through building and implementing concrete applications. We are closely monitoring such developments, and aim to integrate ESSNet Big Data recommendations into the CEEMID workflow &lt;a href=&#34;/publication/creating_better_2015/&#34;&gt;similarly to&lt;/a&gt; earlier ESSnet Culture recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;google-trends&#34;&gt;Google Trends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Trends creates a fully anonymous sample of Google search traffic. Because of the way Google allows the use of Google Trends and scales results, it is very complicated to use Google Trends across regions and countries.  However, our experience shows that Google Trends is an excellent short-term forecasting tool for ticket sales.  It also means that it can serve as a good estimator for ticket sales for regions and territories where few reliable data sources exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/seasonality_plot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CEE concert seasonality analysis&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;geolocational-data&#34;&gt;Geolocational data&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/3lW8bhQ2fbY&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Impact Assessment of Music Industry</title>
      <link>/usecase/impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 19:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/impact/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Economic impact assessments, such as multiplier calculations, direct, indirect and induced employment-, tax-, value added effects calculations are very often needed for larger grants, or the design of grant calls; illegal state aid must be avoided, for example, when designing film tax shelters; or considering various policy options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such calculations require in the background very large amount of highly structure statistical data, which is very difficult to obtain and work with for non-specialist.   Such data must be accompanied by internal financial data or user survey data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;iotables&#34;&gt;iotables&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My open source &lt;a href=&#34;http://iotables.ceemid.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;iotables&lt;/a&gt; software, released within the scope of the rOpenGov collaboration, is aimed at correctly structuring data and conducting must of the algebraic work related to these tasks. Read &lt;a href=&#34;/post/iotables_04/&#34;&gt;more about iotables&lt;/a&gt; among my blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am working together with &lt;a href=&#34;http://kulkal.cz/?lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;KulKal&lt;/a&gt; to make this online cultural calculator usable in all EU member states in the future using some of the features of iotables. Our cooperation started with using some of iotables and CEEMID data in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sharedcities.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Shared Cities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;impact-assessment&#34;&gt;Impact assessment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Economic impact assessment, apart from the use of highly structured national accounts data and algebraic knowledge require organization or national association specific financial data, accounting data or user survey data.  Currently I am working on various applications to standardize these tools, so that each festival organizer, music export office, film fund and tax shelter and other similar organization can use it according to its needs.  While I do not believe that economic impact assessment for large grants or policy evaluation can be fully automated, the most painful part of the process, the gathering of correctly structured data and the most difficult calculations can be automated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creation of the economic impact analysis of the Hungarian film production and extending the Hungarian tax shelter in cooperation with OrienTax.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Economic impact assessment of the Slovak music industry within the &lt;a href=&#34;/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34;&gt;Slovak Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ex ante&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/project/grants/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;grant assessement&lt;/a&gt; for Hungary&amp;rsquo;s Hangfoglaló program&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying Remuneration</title>
      <link>/usecase/pcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/pcr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Private Copying Remuneration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PCR PCR PCR&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation of the Slovak Music Industry Report 2019</title>
      <link>/talk/slovak_report19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/slovak_report19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The venue is &lt;a href=&#34;http://vecko.sk/kontakt/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;V klub, Národné Osvetové Centrum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovak Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The whole report can be downloaded for free from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.soza.sk/aktuality/235/soza-zverej%C5%88uje-historicky-prvu-spravu-o-slovenskom-hudobnom-priemysle&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;homepage of SOZA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press reports in Slovak:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SME: &lt;a href=&#34;Čítajte viac: https://domov.sme.sk/c/22084685/soza-predstavila-historicky-prvu-spravu-o-slovenskom-hudobnom-priemysle.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SOZA predstavila prvú Správu o slovenskom hudobnom priemysle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kreatívna Europa: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cedslovakia.eu/clanky/sprava-o-slovenskom-hudobnom-priemysle&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Historicky prvá Správa o slovenskom hudobnom priemysle prináša okrem analýz aj odporúčania pre budúcnosť&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Hungarian:
Új Szó: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ujszo.com/kultura/tudomanyosan-a-hazai-zeneiparrol&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tudományosan a hazai zeneiparról&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/86x5wKAlsIetxA&#34; width=&#34;595&#34; height=&#34;485&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom:5px&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel/spva-o-hudobnom-priemysle-na-slovensku-sharpe-2018&#34; title=&#34;Spáva o hudobnom priemysle na Slovensku&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Spáva o hudobnom priemysle na Slovensku&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dániel Antal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMID</title>
      <link>/project/ceemid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ceemid/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/tags/ceemid/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CEEMID&lt;/a&gt; (Central and Eastern European Music Industry Databases)  was created out of necessity following a CISAC Good Governance Seminar for European Societies in 2013.  The adoption of European single market and copyright rules, and the increased activity of competition authority and regulators required a more structured approach to set collective royalty and compensations tariffs in the region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014 three societies, Artisjus, HDS and SOZA realized that need to make further efforts to modernize the way they measure their own economic impact, the economic value of their licenses to remain competitive in advocating the interests vis-&amp;#224;-vis domestic governments, international organizations like CISAC and GESAC and the European Union. They signed a Memorandum of Understanding with their consultant to set up the CEEMID databases and to harmonize their efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CEEMID by designed aimed to follow the best European practices on statistical harmonization and was already featured as an innovative &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/creating_better_2015/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;best practice&lt;/a&gt; in the 40th anniversary of Pan European Surveying seminar in 2015.  As an initiative born out of necessity, it aimed fill in the gaps of underdeveloped official cultural statics by following the guidelines of Eurostat&amp;rsquo;s ESSNet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the originally envisioned, centralized, permission-based data structure, due to practical considerations, CEEMID switched to a more flexible, decentralized approach. This approach is based on continuous data integration, which requires permissions to use business confidential information only in use. This allowed a rapid extension of CEEMID to the whole of Europe and go even beyond.  As a result of continous data integration it already includes hundreds of indicators foreseen in all pillars of the planned European Music Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CEEMID works together with music granting agencies, music export offices and collective management societies to reach a representative segment of all professional, semi-professional and amateur artists in the countries covered: Hungary, Slovakia and Croatia, which will be extended this year to the Czech Republic and Serbia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-sources&#34;&gt;Data sources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nationally representative &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/usecase/cap/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CAP surveys&lt;/a&gt; of music users and film viewers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anonymous &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/usecase/musicians/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CEEMID Music Professional Surveys&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CEEMID Audiovisual Professional Surveys&lt;/em&gt; about their work, incomes and costs. See example &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/career_path/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Big data sources from various geolocational applications about events and location visits &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3lW8bhQ2fbY&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;small video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Automatic data retrieval from open data sources, including statistical data and EU-funded research. See example &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/how_many_ever_pay/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;continous-data-integration&#34;&gt;Continous data integration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While CEEMID is aware of and uses the metadata of CISAC&amp;rsquo;s, IFPI&amp;rsquo;s, EAO&amp;rsquo;s, and other industry sources&amp;rsquo; data, it does not contain this data, only when a user with permission for the use of these industry sources requires the integration of such data with other CEEMID data, or user-specific data.  While this approach makes sharing results more cumbersome, it provided a path to increase the number of useful indicators from a few dozens to around a thousand. Furthermore, it exponentially increases the value of CISAC&amp;rsquo;s, IFPI&amp;rsquo;s or EAO&amp;rsquo;s data, especially when designing better royalty rates, or creating economic evidence for litigation. Take a look at a simple, non-confidential example &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/cee_mini_17/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CEEMID Music Professional Surveys are anonymous surveys about the live music and recording markets and granting schemes.  The surveys have been filled out by about 4000 musicians, technicians, managers (and 2000 filmmakers) about the tour destinations, concert budgets and average audiences, various royalty receipts from streaming services, physical and digital sales, YouTube, Bandcamp.  We are also creating comparable statistics with all EU national statistics on life satisfaction, economic expectations, income and economic situation and other characteristics of music and filmmaker professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CEEMID makes sure that the Client&amp;rsquo;s data (collective management organizations, music distributors, music export offices, music granting agencies) are correctly integrated with our survey data, statistical and big data sources, with industry data and the Client&amp;rsquo;s own transactional financial, licensing, granting or processed data. We are handling professionally data errors, missing data, currency translations and other problem areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-cases&#34;&gt;Use Cases&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In combination with collective management data and industry data the music professional surveys can help establish the value of certain rights, or estimate the compensation needed for home copying or the value transfer to platforms like YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In combination with granting data, it can be used for both ex ante evaluation to design better aimed, more cost-efficient and helpful grant calls, or to ex post evaluate the efficiency of grants and the (perceived) honesty and professionalism of the granting process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In combination with the anonymized State51 test data set, it can support machine learning and deep learning (AI) algorithms to establish the potential foreign markets of certain songs, artists or national repertoires, or asses the value of recordings to optimize promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My economic impact package, iotables, has a much updated released on CRAN</title>
      <link>/post/iotables_04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/iotables_04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/latestdoi/108267715&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/108267715.svg&#34; alt=&#34;DOI&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This package was related to several of my works for Slovak, Hungarian and Croatian music industry and the Hungarian Film Fund, and my collaboration with Eeconomic impacT s.r.o in the Czech Republic. My R package downloads symmetric input-output and related tax, margins, use tables from the Eurostat bulk data warehouse, and organizes them for macroeconomic analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analytical functions of the package create the usual economic impact analysis, including direct effects, multipliers on gross value added, employment, CO2 or other factors. The package creates a programmatic interface to compare economic impact changes in time, or compare any country with any country in the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The package is accompanied by three articles (or ‘vignettes’).  The &lt;a href=&#34;http://iotables.ceemid.eu/articles/germany_1990.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Germany 1990&lt;/a&gt; re-creataes almost all of the practical examples of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/documents/3859598/5902113/KS-RA-07-013-EN.PDF/b0b3d71e-3930-4442-94be-70b36cea9b39?version=1.0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Eurostat Manual of Supply, Use and Input-Output Tables&lt;/a&gt; by Jörg Beutel.  This may be used as a tutorial to input-ouput analysis or understanding the package interface. Furthermore, it creates as a verification tool in the package testthat infrastructure to make sure that the functions correctly return all published, verified examples by Prof. Beutel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://iotables.ceemid.eu/articles/united_kingdom_2010.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;United Kingdom Input-Output Analyitcal Tables&lt;/a&gt; article similarly recreates the analytical results, such as GVA and employment cost effects for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://webarchive.nationalarchives.gov.uk/20160114044923tf_/http://www.ons.gov.uk/ons/rel/input-output/input-output-analytical-tables/2010/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;United Kingdom 2010&lt;/a&gt; table.  While the current UK tables and standard Eurstat tables are somewhat different, this table is accompanied by Richard Wild’s excellent article and published analytical results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://iotables.ceemid.eu/articles/working_with_eurostat.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Working with Eurostat data article&lt;/a&gt; shows how to work with real-life, current, SNA2010 compatible data from the Eurostat data warehouse. It contains some comparative results between Czechia and Slovakia.  The package is in itself is extending the functionality of the eurostat package, and it is released with eurostat in the rOpenGov community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Access and Participation surveys</title>
      <link>/usecase/cap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/cap/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Cultural Access and Participation Surveys are standardized surveys designed to measure various market-based and non-market based (amateur, liturgical, etc.) cultural activities, including concerts, streaming subscriptions, singing, etc.  They are based on various quantative sociological models and had been standardized by the Eurostat working group &lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/assets/eac/culture/library/reports/ess-net-report_en.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ESSNet-Culture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CEEMID CAP surveys are usually live interviews that allow cross-country comparison, and they are used both for market forecasting, market analytics, royalty and compensation value setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-europe-2013&#34;&gt;CAP Europe 2013&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use the data of the CAP 2013 survey for cross-country comparisons and for model calibration, because it includes all EU countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/cee_concert_demography_16x9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Comparative Demography with CAP EU 2013&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-europe-2007&#34;&gt;CAP Europe 2007&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use the data of the CAP 2007 survey for understanding cross-country dynamics and long-term changes, because it includes all EU countries. For example, we can determine in which countries visit &lt;code&gt;Generation Z&lt;/code&gt; 20-years-old people more concerts or cinemas than their &lt;code&gt;Generation X&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Generation Y&lt;/code&gt; peers when they were 20-years-old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2019&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2019 survey fieldwork is under way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2018&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2018&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2018 survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors, particularly to calculate the equitable remuneration for private copying, the value transfer to YouTube and other media platforms, and the development of the audidence for Hungarian films.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2017&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2017 survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors, particularly to calculate the equitable remuneration for private copying. A separate mini-CAP survey was designed to capture the value transfer to YouTube, which was later incorporated into the CAP Hungary 2018-2019 surveys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-croatia-2017&#34;&gt;CAP Croatia 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CAP Croatia 2017 survey was designed for the creation of the Private Copying in Croatia report, which is prepared for the forthcoming Croatian Copyright legislation changes on private copying and the value gap.  The survey was conducted by Hendall on a sample of 800 respondents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-slovakaia-2015&#34;&gt;CAP Slovakaia 2015&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CAP Slovakia 2015 survey was designed as a part of a larger survey that also incorporated attitudes towards Slovak culture and non-standard survey questions designed by Focus.  The CAP Survey was used to create the &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Slovak Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt; and to make various legislative impact assessment presentations during the modification of the Slovak Copyright Law on private copying and radio quotas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2015&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2015&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2015 survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors. It was used in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gvh.hu/sajtoszoba/sajtokozlemenyek/2016_os_sajtokozlemenyek/az_ures_hordozoi_dij_fogasztoi_visszaigenylesenek_.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;competition authority case&lt;/a&gt; related to the Hungarian private copying regime and in a consulting project related to better finding the audience of Hungarian cinemas in their domestic theatrical market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The survey was conducted by TNS Hoffmann (currently named Kantar Hoffmann.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2014&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2014&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CAP Hungary 2014 was a non-representative, large-sample online survey to pilot the later surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Professionals surveys</title>
      <link>/usecase/musicians/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/musicians/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The three income streams model is essentially a value chain based model that was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldcat.org/title/music-business-and-recording-industry-delivering-music-in-the-21st-century/oclc/969999538&amp;amp;referer=brief_results&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;developed in the United States&lt;/a&gt; and adopted by the European Commission’s Joint Research Center for European CCI policy purposes &lt;a href=&#34;http://ftp.jrc.es/EURdoc/JRC69816.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pdf download&lt;/a&gt;. We made minor adaptations in the three income model for applicability in Central Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in the original American model sound recordings are the “main” income stream, currently, especially in Central Europe the live performance stream earns the most income for a typical musician. The author’s stream is the oldest, traditionally and analytically first part of the music industry that includes revenue streams based on musical works exploited by music publishers and via author’s CMO societies such as HDS. In the US it is called the publishing stream, but in Central Europe it is dominated by authors’ societies, so we modified the label.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/three_income_streams_croatia.png&#34; alt=&#34;The CEEMID Adoptation of the Three Income Stream Model&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ceemid-music-professionals-2019&#34;&gt;CEEMID Music Professionals 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CEEMID Music Professionals Survey is under way in 12 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;music-professionals-hungary-2018&#34;&gt;Music Professionals Hungary 2018&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors, particularly to calculate the equitable remuneration for private copying. Furthermore, we cooperated with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mokk.bme.hu/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MOKK Centre for Media Research and Education&lt;/a&gt; in a not-yet published research about gender roles and career perspectives of women in the Hungarian music scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;music-professionals-hungary-2017&#34;&gt;Music Professionals Hungary 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This survey was designed for a full market analysis in Hungary on the music and audiovisual sectors, particularly to calculate the equitable remuneration for private copying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;music-professionals-slovakia-2017&#34;&gt;Music Professionals Slovakia 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This survey was used  update the &lt;a href=&#34;/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34;&gt;Slovak Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;music-professionals-hungary-2015&#34;&gt;Music Professionals Hungary 2015&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data and intelligence of CEEMID was used in Hungary to create an &lt;a href=&#34;/post/cstp_15/&#34;&gt;ex ante evaluation&lt;/a&gt; of the new Cseh Tamás Program to support popular music development in Hungary. The programme is currently named Hangfoglaló.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;music-professionals-croatia-2015&#34;&gt;Music Professionals Croatia 2015&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Music Professionals Croatia 2015 survey was designed for the creation of the Private Copying in Croatia report, which is prepared for the forthcoming Croatian Copyright legislation changes on private copying and the value gap. It was first presented on the &lt;a href=&#34;/post/makk15/&#34;&gt;MAKK 2015 conference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;musicians-slovakia-2015&#34;&gt;Musicians Slovakia 2015&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This survey was used  to create the &lt;a href=&#34;/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/&#34;&gt;Slovak Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt; and to make various legislative impact assessment presentations during the modification of the Slovak Copyright Law on private copying and radio quotas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;musicians-hungary-2014&#34;&gt;Musicians Hungary 2014&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This survey was used  to create the &lt;a href=&#34;/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/&#34;&gt;Hungarian Music Industry Report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
