<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Antal, CFA on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Daniel Antal, CFA on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMID</title>
      <link>/project/ceemid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ceemid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CEEMID (Central and Eastern European Music Industry Databases) were created by Consultant Daniel Antal, CFA and three collective management societies in 2014 as a platform to collect, share and integrate data for royalty price setting, economic impact evaluation and taxation on music. The aim was to bring emerging market stakeholders to the information level of mature market stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CEEMID uses various forms of data collection.
* Nationally representative surveys of music users and film viewers
* Anonymous surveys of musicians and filmmakers about their work, incomes and costs
* Big data sources from various geolocational applications about events and location visits
* Automatic data retrieval from open data sources
* Industry data sources such as the CISAC and IFPI global reports, the European Audiovisual Yearbook, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CEEMID Music Professional Surveys are anonymous surveys about the live music and recording markets and granting schemes.  The surveys have been filled out by about 4000 musicians, technicians, managers (and 2000 filmmakers) about the tour destinations, concert budgets and average audiences, various royalty receipts from streaming services, physical and digital sales, YouTube, Bandcamp.  We are also creating comparable statistics with all EU national statistics on life satisfaction, economic expectations, income and economic situation and other characteristics of music and filmmaker professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CEEMID works together with music granting agencies, music export offices and collective management societies to reach a representative segment of all professional, semi-professional and amateur artists in the countries covered: Hungary, Slovakia and Croatia, which will be extended this year to the Czech Republic and Serbia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We make sure that the Client&amp;rsquo;s data (collective management organizations, music distributors, music export offices, music granting agencies) are correctly integrated with our survey data, statistical and big data sources, with industry data and the Client&amp;rsquo;s own transactional financial, licensing, granting or processed data. We are handling professionally data errors, missing data, currency translations and other problem areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also offering the opportunity to new partners do start surveying in Belarus, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Bulgaria and Lithuania.  In these countries we are aiming to create smaller data samples that allow a factual comparison with the five fully covered countries and the United Kingdom as a benchmark, and to pave the way to include these countries in the core CEEMID data collection on a yearly or biannual basis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My economic impact package, iotables, has a much updated released on CRAN</title>
      <link>/post/iotables_04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/iotables_04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/latestdoi/108267715&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/108267715.svg&#34; alt=&#34;DOI&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This package was related to several of my works for Slovak, Hungarian and Croatian music industry and the Hungarian Film Fund, and my collaboration with Eeconomic impacT s.r.o in the Czech Republic. My R package downloads symmetric input-output and related tax, margins, use tables from the Eurostat bulk data warehouse, and organizes them for macroeconomic analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analytical functions of the package create the usual economic impact analysis, including direct effects, multipliers on gross value added, employment, CO2 or other factors. The package creates a programmatic interface to compare economic impact changes in time, or compare any country with any country in the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The package is accompanied by three articles (or ‘vignettes’).  The &lt;a href=&#34;http://iotables.ceemid.eu/articles/germany_1990.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Germany 1990&lt;/a&gt; re-creataes almost all of the practical examples of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/documents/3859598/5902113/KS-RA-07-013-EN.PDF/b0b3d71e-3930-4442-94be-70b36cea9b39?version=1.0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Eurostat Manual of Supply, Use and Input-Output Tables&lt;/a&gt; by Jörg Beutel.  This may be used as a tutorial to input-ouput analysis or understanding the package interface. Furthermore, it creates as a verification tool in the package testthat infrastructure to make sure that the functions correctly return all published, verified examples by Prof. Beutel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://iotables.ceemid.eu/articles/united_kingdom_2010.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;United Kingdom Input-Output Analyitcal Tables&lt;/a&gt; article similarly recreates the analytical results, such as GVA and employment cost effects for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://webarchive.nationalarchives.gov.uk/20160114044923tf_/http://www.ons.gov.uk/ons/rel/input-output/input-output-analytical-tables/2010/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;United Kingdom 2010&lt;/a&gt; table.  While the current UK tables and standard Eurstat tables are somewhat different, this table is accompanied by Richard Wild’s excellent article and published analytical results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://iotables.ceemid.eu/articles/working_with_eurostat.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Working with Eurostat data article&lt;/a&gt; shows how to work with real-life, current, SNA2010 compatible data from the Eurostat data warehouse. It contains some comparative results between Czechia and Slovakia.  The package is in itself is extending the functionality of the eurostat package, and it is released with eurostat in the rOpenGov community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royalty Setting</title>
      <link>/usecase/royalty_setting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usecase/royalty_setting/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Cultural Access and Participation Surveys are standardized surveys designed to measure various market-based and non-market based (amateur, liturgical, etc.) cultural activities, including concerts, streaming subscriptions, singing, etc.  They are based on various quantative sociological models and had been standardized by the Eurostat working group &lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/assets/eac/culture/library/reports/ess-net-report_en.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ESSNet-Culture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CEEMID CAP surveys are usually live interviews that allow cross-country comparison, and they are used both for market forcasting, market analytics, royalty and compensation value setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-europe-2013&#34;&gt;CAP Europe 2013&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use the data of the CAP 2013 survey for cross-country comparisons and for model calibration, because it includes all EU countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2018&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2018&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2017&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-croatia-2017&#34;&gt;CAP Croatia 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-slovakaia-2015&#34;&gt;CAP Slovakaia 2015&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2015&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2015&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-hungary-2014&#34;&gt;CAP Hungary 2014&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cap-europe-2007&#34;&gt;CAP EUrope 2007&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use the data of the CAP 2007 survey for understanding cross-country dynamics and long-term changes, because it includes all EU countries. For example, we can determine in which countries visit &lt;code&gt;Generation Z&lt;/code&gt; 20-years-old people more concerts or cinemas than their &lt;code&gt;Generation X&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Generation Y&lt;/code&gt; peers when they were 20-years-old.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Reports</title>
      <link>/project/market_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/market_report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been creating market reports for 20 years, mainly in emerging markets where data is scarce and often has little history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting as a junior consultant, I learned a lot about data acquisition. Later I held a &amp;lsquo;strategic information management&amp;rsquo; position in the Ministry of Economy and Transport in Hungary with oversight on the national statistical data collection. As a senior consultant and a former lecture, I used to train junior colleagues and journalists on data acquisition. Nowadays most of my data collection is automatized via custom software developed for CEEMID. This leaves a bit of extra time to think about novel ways to add to the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work completely in the reproducible research paradigm, where my consulting slide presentations and reports include all the data used, the program code to manipulate, organize them, and the models applied for forecasting, calculation, estimation.  As a CFA charterholder I follow very strict data retention and transparency rules and I found this the state of the art method to comply with the ever growing client and regulatory expectations in this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Press the tag below to see more examples&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eurpoean Comparison: How Many People Ever Pay For Music, Film or Software</title>
      <link>/post/how_many_ever_pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how_many_ever_pay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our recent private copying reports we compiled European survey data relevant to analysis.  In Europe, there is a big difference between the use of electronic entertainment devices in richer and poorer countries. Nevertheless, the real difference is between the number of people who sometimes and who never pay for downloaded music, films and software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some countries of Europe, less then 10 percent of the population ever pays for the content that is loaded to their computers, smartphones and tablets.  These survey data, accompanied by other objective data, can help explaining 96% of the variance among digital music sales levels within the EU countries, and it is highly relevant in calculating the economic benefit of home copying for users, and the harm for rightsholders.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovak Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/post/sharpe_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sharpe_18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can review the slides here.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide1.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Slovak Music Industry Report&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide1.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide2.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Music industry has a great potential to create jobs…&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide2.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide3.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Mapping the Slovak Music Industry&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide3.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide4.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Mapping the Slovak Music industry&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide4.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide5.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;The importance of the changing VAT regulation&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide5.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide6.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;The need of stronger copyright protection and higher royalty values&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide6.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide7.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Critical size in the global market requires strong national players&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide7.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide8.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Part of an animation, not animated here.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide8.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide9.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Short-term growth with foreign revenues&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slide9.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slidez10.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Get involved&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/sharpe_18/gallery/Slidez10.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R</title>
      <link>/project/r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The symmetric input-output tables (SIOTs) are complex statistical products that present inter-related statistics in a predefined structure. They are often found in spreadsheets that follow this structure, or in the case Eurostat in a data repository. In both cases they in reproducible research must be downloaded and restructured to programmatically accessible form. Often these highly structured statistics need to be analyzed together with other data, for example, when employment effects and multipliers are calculated. In this case processing the employment data to SIOT conforming format is a significant preprocessing challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iotables are exactly designed for these tasks. Currently the package downloads and processes standardized European SIOTs conforming to the latest statistical regulations, i.e. SIOTs starting from the year 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to test the analytical functions of the package and to have a manageable sized example data set, we use the real-life data from the Eurostat manual. The calculation of induced effects (Type-II multipliers) are following the Input-Output Multipliers Specification Sheet and Supporting Material, Spicosa Project Report. The analytical functions are tested against this example, too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEE Mini Recording Industry Workshop</title>
      <link>/post/cee_mini_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cee_mini_17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I presented my market view and experience with distinguished colleagues from the Baltic states, Central Europe and the Balkan, representatives of WIN and IFPI and the international indie distributor State 51. We had a lively discussion on why emerging markets are emerging so slowly in the new digital music business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a decade of decline due to piracy and change in business model, the global music business is steadily growing.  However, defying some economic expectation, to growth is stronger in mature markets than in most emerging markets, and most of the global growth came from the United States. The dollar-based IFPI Global Music Report hides the fact that mature and emerging Europe is truly lagging behind the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The European music scene is very fragmented, has many languages and the lack of critical market size often leads to neglect by innovative global players. In a world where most music is soled by big data driven algorithms in subscription streams, the lack of large repertoires, data analytics capabilities and critical audience masses puts the smaller European repertoires into a competitive disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/cee_mini_17/gallery/digital_gap.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Digital gap: share in household recreational spending and digital music revenues.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/cee_mini_17/gallery/digital_gap.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
      
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/cee_mini_17/gallery/featured.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;The source of growth has been mainly the United States so far.&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/post/cee_mini_17/gallery/featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a very interesting discussion that will lead to hopefully many new initiatives on a number of problems, including low market prices in collectively managed and private channels, distribution problems, the difficulties and opportunities in regional cooperation and a number of other topics.
The presentation and the working paper is not public, but the similar workshops in the future may help growing a more mature network of CEE industry players and the adoption of new business models, pricing and promotion methods and more coordinated planning and marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMPC session: Licensing, How To Tackle The Value Gap And A Discussion On Licensing Initiatives</title>
      <link>/talk/ceempc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/ceempc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More information in the &lt;a href=&#34;./post/ceemp/&#34;&gt;blogpost&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMP Session: Licensing, How To Tackle The Value Gap And A Discussion on Licensing Initiatives</title>
      <link>/post/ceempc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ceempc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CEEMID had the honor to participate in the third panel of CEEMP in Warsaw together with Ben McEwen from ICE; Jules Parker from Spotify and Dominic Houston from Netflix, and Chris Butler from Music Sales, who is also the chairperson of ICMP. Our panel was moderated by Nigel Elderton from peermusic, who is also the new chairperson of PRS in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jules from Spotify spoke about their new initiative, Spotify for Publishers.  Spotify pays out about 20% of its royalties to publishers.  Because the labels are the bigger stakeholders, they often do not provide the necessary information for work identification in the case of publishers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic from Netflix is already one of the biggest buyers of music, and I believe that his company’s footprint will just continue growing.  His time buys licenses only 10% of their music from publishers. They mainly use original film music, and to a significant degree, catalogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben made a presentation about their innovation efforts at ICE digital rights management. Working with some of the largest repertoires represented by PRS, GEMA and STIM, they really offer world class services. Next year they promise to scale services to smaller repertoires, who can immediately benefit from low-cost identification from the cleaned data of these large societies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital gap between household cultural spending and CE / S European music industry revenues in the digital world
Comparing household cultural spending with digital music revenues in Europe’s main regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel’s short presentation highlighted the fact that the CEE region’s is much richer in terms of household cultural and recreational spending that it is thought by the music industry, because the music industry is really lagging its Western and Nordic peers in tapping into this pool of money.  There are many reasons for this, all a bit touched upon the other speaker’s issues, and their implementation difficulties n the CEE region, especially different revenue stream breakup, strong collective management and relatively underdeveloped publishing.  The region is about 200% or more below its benchmark in the sales we were talking about in this session.  The conversation will continue in Brussels, Prague, Budapest, Bratislava and Warsaw in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grants</title>
      <link>/project/grants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/grants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Governments, the EU, international organizations and private donors often support causes of public interest with grants and donations. In some cases, these grants are aimed to help starting or sustaining economic activities. In other cases, they are supporting artistic activities or education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been involved in the professional assessment of granting schemes and grant applications since 2000. I have learned and taught various assessment methods to evaluated EU and national grants to support valuable public infrastructure, energy savings, health investments and other causes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I work with the creative industries, I had transferred some of this methodology to supporting music and film creation. Grants are essential to maintain the diversity and artistic quality of European music and films, and they can be essential to jump start young industries like smartphone application development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience, many music grants schemes are inefficient, because they are not based on an objective assessment of musician’s needs and market conditions. In some cases, they are supporting politically interesting ‘pet projects’ that have little lasting effects. Occasionally they give too large or too many grants for certain activities that crowds out private investment of artists.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing</title>
      <link>/project/pricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pricing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At a very early stage of my career I specialized in regulated prices and acquired a second degree in Economic Regulation and Competition Policy.  As an advisor to the minister, I set up a regulatory framework with new regulation for Hungarian freight railways.  As a regulator or as a consultant to the authority I participated in price reviews.  As a consultant to regulated industries, I helped making legally allowed pricing decisions or helped to challenge regulatory decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strategic pricing decisions have a profound impact on the value of companies and regulatory targets, too.  As a CFA charterholder, and as a person trained in competition policy and regulation, I understand both aspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first decade of the 21st century I worked in newly liberalized industries, including telecommunications, banks, insurance, transport and energy.    Later I focused more and more services with intangible assets, including data pricing and royalty pricing where I consider myself one of the most accomplished professionals in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Press the tag below to see more examples&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royalties</title>
      <link>/project/royalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/royalties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Royalties are earnings on intellectual properties.  In music, they are the earnings of the music composer, the performer and the producer and the recorded performance.  Creators of films, books, software, and other artistic works or intellectual products are entitled to various forms of royalties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many royalties are collectively managed, like the musicians pay after radio or restaurant plays.  Other royalties, like revenues of app developers, are directly or indirectly paid to them by the buyer of their products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the valuation of intellectual properties and their resulting fair earnings in the forms in royalties appears to be simple in economic theory, in practice it is very complicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last decade I have used many valuation methods to establish the fair (price) level of various royalties or the fair value of an intellectual property. Most of these assignments went around the value of music.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Musician Career Paths</title>
      <link>/post/career_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/career_path/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the 20th century the first career step was to get on stage and create a credible live performance. After several years on the stage musician’s got a recording contract, and usually even later they registered their first composition. The recording stream was the most important revenue source. The making of a record was expensive and offered considerable royalties or advances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 21st century the live music stream is far more important than the recordings. Creating recordings is much cheaper and stage performances are expensive. Musicians usually create their music, also register it as a music work and offer it to the public on an online portfolio of mp3 downloads, YouTube and music streams.  Often they are booked for their first live performance after publishing a recording.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it mean for the musician and the manager?  First and foremost that traditional career development strategies do not work anymore. A convincing stage performance is mandatory with a good touring strategy.  Recordings are often not profitable, but equally important in building the audience. Making the recording stream a revenue stream instead of the cost stream requires a very good understanding of the costs and benefits of the different digital channels. CEEMID also contains market information on these issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Career information in CEEMID
* Milestones of the musician’s career
* Level of professionalization, secondary career paths
* Income level and basic live standards information
* Production and concert volumes
* Revenue breakup in all the three major income streams, i.e. publishing, recording and live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data is available for Croatia, Hungary and Slovakia. Breakup by genre, gender, birth year, age cohort, capital  / countryside is also possible.  Similar surveys are being conducted in the film production industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Growth of the Hungarian Popular Music Repertoire: Who Creates It And How Does It Find An Audience</title>
      <link>/publication/made_in_hungary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/made_in_hungary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being visible in the world is always difficult in the Central and Eastern European region.  Made in Hungary is the first book in the Popular Music Studies series of Routledge from the region.   A description of our first datasets, the motivation of the research and the CEEMID concept is laid out as a closing, quantitative chapter in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:0px&#34; src=&#34;https://books.google.hu/books?id=9KvZDQAAQBAJ&amp;lpg=PA1980&amp;pg=PA1980&amp;output=embed&#34; width=500 height=700&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
