<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Social Distancing in Europe</title>
      <link>/post/yes-delft-co-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/yes-delft-co-lab/</guid>
      <description>People around the world are facing newer and newer exponential charts everyday. We’re all hoping for new information about the progress against the coronavirus. Unfortunately, the vast majority of these charts is meaningless. In fact, coronavirus case counts are meaningless, unless they are done with very heavy statistical knowledge, and even then they are very messy. Countries have different testing and hospitalization protocols, death certificating standards, and there are less and more trustworthy governments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crisis Recovery in the CEE &amp; SEE Creative &amp; Cultural Sectors</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-09-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-04-09-recovery/</guid>
      <description>My presentation provided for the Slovak music industry stakeholders in this dialogue are not made available in a more general form, because the problems in Croatia, Hungary, Poland,  Slovakia, and to a great extent in the broader region including Austria, Slovenia and Czechia are very similar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documenting CEEMID For Open Data Use</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-24-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 13:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-24-documentation/</guid>
      <description>The Central European Music Industry Report 2020 was updated with a technical annex that points out to the new wiki documentation website of CEEMID to make our work more accessible for designing the European Music Observatory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of COVID-19 On Creative &amp; Cultural Industries</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-18-covid19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-18-covid19/</guid>
      <description>I was asked to contribute an article to the COVID-19 economic crisis series of the Hungarian business weekly and portal hgv.hu.  While the article is only available in Hungarian, and behind a paywall, it draws on experiences that are very similar across the CEE region, and in some cases, in most the European Union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Empirical Approach To Modernizing The Cultural and Creative Occupations and Skills Classifications</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-11-esco/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 12:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-11-esco/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID has a large enough answer pool for an empirical clustering of occupations. We are able to perform clustering of job descriptions, earnings, educational levels, and work output (such as films, documentaries, TV programmes, live music performances, music compositions, etc) to empirically create groups with a “set of jobs whose main tasks and duties are characterised by a high degree of similarity” in terms of economic activity and work output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programatic Approach To Work With European Regional Data Panels</title>
      <link>/post/2020-02-13-regional_eurostat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 12:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-02-13-regional_eurostat/</guid>
      <description>My open source program code was released within the 3.6.1 version of eurostat R package, making the painful boundary alignment with frequent region border changes, and resulting data imputation work automatic and less error-prone. As a result, more and more of my work, and particularly the music indicators of CEEMID are becoming available on provincial/regional level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCS Ecosystems: Evidence-Driven CCI Policy &amp; The Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</guid>
      <description>The Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020 was presented as a case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budapest Showcase Hub &amp; Conference 2019</title>
      <link>/post/2019-11-18-bush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-11-18-bush/</guid>
      <description>We had a very interesting discussion day on the Budapest Showcase Hub with the regional independent labels in the workshop hosted by HAIL and with some concert promoters and music educators in the main conference program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Czech Music Development Program &amp; Comparative Market Research</title>
      <link>/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</guid>
      <description>A Progress Report on the Czech Music Development Program and problems in an international context. We would like to invite any Czech stakeholders, or even individuals to join our Research Consortium, because in the music sector, all organization are microenterprise or small enterprise sized, they usually have no significant market research, innovation and strategic HR management capacities. We hope to give them in each country useful tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying in Croatia</title>
      <link>/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</guid>
      <description>My study, Private Copying in Croatia, argues for an overhaul of the Croatian private copying remuneration scheme and gives some empirical evidence for the transposition of the DSM Directive. Even for those who are not interested in royalties, the first 3 chapters offer a very interesting introduction on how people listen to music, how musicians make music and how people copy it in the 21st century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central European Music Industry Report Presentation</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 08:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/</guid>
      <description>We had the first public and panel discussion of the forthcoming Central European Music Industry Report.  After mapping and analysing in depth the music industries of several CEE countries, I put together with the help of Consolidated Independent and state51 a regional report in previously unseen detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Market Growth on European Markets</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-24_index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-24_index/</guid>
      <description>Total national sales reflect the growing number of subscribers, the price, the exchange rate, and many factors that are not important for an artists or music label. Instead we design indexes that show the real growth for a typical domestic or foreign rightsholder in a country.  The aim is to provide useful sales and performance guidance for smaller countries, genres and exporting destinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Market Shares on Spotify Hitlists</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</guid>
      <description>Which are the European countries that can successfully export songs on a streaming platform? What are the differences in cross-border hits from the UK, France, Germany, the Netherlands and Sweden?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musicians’ Living Standards And Life Satisfaction In The CEE Region</title>
      <link>/post/life_sat_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/life_sat_19/</guid>
      <description>Career in music can lead to higher life satisfaction than other similarly paid jobs in Europe.  However, music market stakeholders should focus on increasing the level of music professional earnings and reducing its variance within the year and over the years, because the material living conditions of musicians is significantly worse than the conditions of the general population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSM Directive, Value Gap &amp; Private Copying Levies</title>
      <link>/post/dsm_pcr_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dsm_pcr_19/</guid>
      <description>We see common threats and common opportunities with the national implementations of the DSM Directive.  While it is not addressing private copying, it is aiming to re-arrange the power balance between users and rightsholders of certain unlicensed, or not fully-licensed and compensated uses. Users will use this opportunity to keep as much as possible from the value transfer to their media platforms, and hardware manufacturers will try to freeze very low private copying remuneration levels in the region. Or worse still: to reduce them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMID Music Professionals Survey 2019</title>
      <link>/post/2019-06-07_ceemid_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-06-07_ceemid_survey/</guid>
      <description>Since most music professional work in microenterprises, or as freelancers, they usually do not participate in economic statistical surveys, and their problems remain hidden from government officials and the general public. This is why we designed an developed an individual-level survey since 2014 which in 2019 already covers more than 10 countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My economic impact package, iotables, has a much updated released on CRAN</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-04_iotables_released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-04_iotables_released/</guid>
      <description>The analytical functions of the package create the usual economic impact analysis, including direct effects, multipliers on gross value added, employment, CO2 or other factors. The package creates a programmatic interface to compare economic impact changes in time, or compare any country with any country in the European Union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eurpoean Comparison: How Many People Ever Pay For Music, Film or Software</title>
      <link>/post/how_many_ever_pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how_many_ever_pay/</guid>
      <description>In Europe, there is a big difference between the use of electronic entertainment devices in richer and poorer countries. Nevertheless, the real difference is between the number of people who sometimes and who never pay for downloaded music, films and software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovak Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/post/sharpe_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sharpe_18/</guid>
      <description>We presented the most important findings of the Slovak Music Industry Report with the project sponsor, Mgr. Tomas Miks, member of SOZA’s management team in the first SHARPE music conference in Bratislava.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEE Mini Recording Industry Workshop</title>
      <link>/post/cee_mini_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cee_mini_17/</guid>
      <description>I presented my market view and experience with distinguished colleagues from the Baltic states, Central Europe and the Balkan, representatives of WIN and IFPI and the international indie distributor State 51. We had a lively discussion on why emerging markets are emerging so slowly in the new digital music business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMP Session: Licensing, How To Tackle The Value Gap And A Discussion on Licensing Initiatives</title>
      <link>/post/ceempc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ceempc/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID had the honor to participate in the third panel of CEEMP in Warsaw together with Ben McEwen from ICE; Jules Parker from Spotify and Dominic Houston from Netflix, and Chris Butler from Music Sales, who is also the chairperson of ICMP. Our panel was moderated by Nigel Elderton from peermusic, who is also the new chairperson of PRS in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Musician Career Paths</title>
      <link>/post/career_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/career_path/</guid>
      <description>In our survey, we ask musicians about the most important milestones of their career and their achievement in the past 12 month. So far we have surveyed more than 2000 music professionals and 900 film production professionals in Croatia, Hungary and Slovakia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Croatian Music Industry</title>
      <link>/post/2016-04-20_makk15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-04-20_makk15/</guid>
      <description>Daniel Antal presented the preliminary findings of the Croatian music industry research in the International Authors’ and Creators’ Conference in Zagreb on 24 November 2015. The presentation was largely based on analysis of various CEEMID databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granting And Policy Evaluation For Musicians In Hungary</title>
      <link>/post/2015-11-12_cstp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-11-12_cstp/</guid>
      <description>The data and intelligence of CEEMID was used in Hungary to create an ex ante evaluation of the new Cseh Tamás Program to support popular music development in Hungary.  Our mandate was to create concrete granting proposals that have a high chance of making a change in terms of the later royalty earning capabilities of artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first national Hungarian Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/post/proart_report_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/proart_report_15/</guid>
      <description>The report was compiled with joining data and knowledge from collective management agencies for composer, producer and performer royalties, and market leading companies Sziget (organizer of Sziget festival and many more festivals), WMMD music distribution company, market-leading Schubert Music Publishing and A38, Hungary’s leading music club, together with producer and audience survey data, tax authority data and other government sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications for tariff setting</title>
      <link>/post/cisac_goodg_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cisac_goodg_13/</guid>
      <description>My short presentation highlighted the fact that the CEE region’s is much richer in terms of household cultural and recreational spending than music publishers believe.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>