<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Empirical Approach To Modernizing The Cultural and Creative Occupations and Skills Classifications</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-11-esco/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 12:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-11-esco/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID has been conducting surveys among music and film professionals for 6 years. So far, about 5000 music and 1500 film professionals filled out our detailed questionnaire about their working conditions, skills, tasks. Some of our surveys were related to training needs assessments, and other professional growth assessments.
The ESCO system builds on occupations, skills and qualifications. Our general experience is that in the music and film industry, because of the lack of life-long learning opportunities, the absence of large employers, low level of unionization, and generally the mixed nature of occupations, informal learning practices play a very important role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programatic Approach To Work With European Regional Data Panels</title>
      <link>/post/2020-02-13-regional_eurostat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 12:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-02-13-regional_eurostat/</guid>
      <description>A very important part of my work is to pre-process data, and integrate various data tables into tidy, comprehensive data tables or databases. This is particularly difficult but rewarding when I work with statistics on sub-national, regional level. While country borders are very rarely change in the world, regional boundaries are changing on average every three years withing the European Union. Putting together data with 2010, 2013, 2017 and the forthcoming 2021 regional boundaries is a very difficult task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCS Ecosystems: Evidence-Driven CCI Policy &amp; The Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent presented and discussed with stakeholders the Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020 as a case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector on the CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.
My presentation was focused around the question on invisibility of the CCI sector in the economic, education and labour policymaking, and the low level of data use in fact-based cultural policy design, and the following policy design problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budapest Showcase Hub &amp; Conference 2019</title>
      <link>/post/2019-11-18-bush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-11-18-bush/</guid>
      <description>We had a very interesting discussion day on the Budapest Showcase Hub with the regional independent labels in the workshop hosted by HAIL and with some concert promoters and music educators in the main conference program.
You can find the full presentation, including slides not shown in the workshop here. The presentation is a self-contained big file of 11Mb, takes time to load.
And here you can review the recordings of the great bands and performers who participated in the showcase festival:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Czech Music Development Program &amp; Comparative Market Research</title>
      <link>/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</guid>
      <description>I was presenting some highlights from the work we started with in the organization of SoundCzech with 25 music professionals representing more than 20 stakeholders in the How We Would Like To Work in the Czech Music Industry in 2020 ex ante evaluation workshop in the context of the comparative Central European Music Industry Report.
You can find the full presentation, including slides not shown in the workshop here. The presentation is a self-contained big file of 20Mb, takes time to load.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying in Croatia</title>
      <link>/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</guid>
      <description>After much delay, the first measurement of licensed use of music, audiovisual content, home copying and value transfer to media platforms in Croatia for a practical update of the private copying remuneration in the country.
You can find the whole study in English, a Croatian language summary and a press release in the Publications section.
The models presented are simplified models of the Hungarian and Slovak models, with less detailed data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central European Music Industry Report Presentation</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 08:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/</guid>
      <description>We had the first public and panel discussion of the forthcoming Central European Music Industry Report. After mapping and analysing in depth the music industries of several CEE countries, I put together with the help of Consolidated Independent and state51 a regional report in previously unseen detail.
You can review the whole presentation here (10Mb self-contained HTML file, takes some time to load).
After mapping and analysing (see most recently Slovakia) in depth the music industries of several CEE countries, with the help of Consolidated Independent I put together a regional report in previously unseen detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Market Growth on European Markets</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-24_index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-24_index/</guid>
      <description>I have never been a great fan of the headline figures reported by the recording industry about streaming growth. I always felt that however dynamic are those charts, artists keep complaining that they do not feel these developments. So I started to decompose those growth figures.
The Global Music Report quotes national streaming revenues on a dollar basis, which contains a lot of currency exchange noise. And behind the national total there are too many factors: subscriber base growth and repertoire growth and the subscription fee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Market Shares on Spotify Hitlists</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</guid>
      <description>If we take a look at the streaming charts of the region, we usually find that the vast majority of the streamed songs are foreign songs - except for Austria, U.S. songs. For comparison, we added a similar, middle-income emerging market (Argentina) and a rich, small-population English-speaking country, Australia to the chart. These countries seem to be in a similar position to the CEE countries.
Arguably, the strongest countries of songwriting are the United States and Brazil - these are the countries that have ran out of the ISRC recording identifier range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musicians’ Living Standards And Life Satisfaction In The CEE Region</title>
      <link>/post/life_sat_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/life_sat_19/</guid>
      <description>In order to get a high-level comparison among the living standards of musicians, we use the standard survey question used in Eurobarometer surveys for decades: how often have had the respondent difficulties with paying bills in the past year? This is a very good starting point because it makes comparable the rough material standards of musicians and other professional groups in the EU, irrespective of local earnings and living costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSM Directive, Value Gap &amp; Private Copying Levies</title>
      <link>/post/dsm_pcr_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dsm_pcr_19/</guid>
      <description>Private copying after 60 years remains a very important way of spreading recorded music, books and audiovisual works, and a very important source of revenue for artists, composers, writers, film writers and performers if managed properly. According to our research, the value of private copying is far bigger these days than when most CEE private copying remuneration mechanisms were set up.
While the new DSM Directive is not addressing these issues, it is aiming to re-arrange the power balance between users and rightsholders of certain unlicensed, or not fully-licensed and compensated uses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMID Music Professionals Survey 2019</title>
      <link>/post/2019-06-07_ceemid_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-06-07_ceemid_survey/</guid>
      <description>The fragmentation of the music business into microenterprises and freelance carriers make the work of a musician very complex. Most musicians do not only fulfill the artistic role of a performer, composer, lyricist or composer. In most cases, artists perform two artistic roles, but it is equally frequent that they perform a different, but still music related engineering, educator or managerial role. Given that that average size of creative enterprises in Europe is less than two people, musicians are forced to do several very different things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My economic impact package, iotables, has a much updated released on CRAN</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-04_iotables_released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-04_iotables_released/</guid>
      <description>This package was related to several of my works for Slovak, Hungarian and Croatian music industry and the Hungarian Film Fund, and my collaboration with Eeconomic impacT s.r.o in the Czech Republic. My R package downloads symmetric input-output and related tax, margins, use tables from the Eurostat bulk data warehouse, and organizes them for macroeconomic analysis.
The analytical functions of the package create the usual economic impact analysis, including direct effects, multipliers on gross value added, employment, CO2 or other factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eurpoean Comparison: How Many People Ever Pay For Music, Film or Software</title>
      <link>/post/how_many_ever_pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how_many_ever_pay/</guid>
      <description>In our recent private copying reports we compiled European survey data relevant to analysis. In Europe, there is a big difference between the use of electronic entertainment devices in richer and poorer countries. Nevertheless, the real difference is between the number of people who sometimes and who never pay for downloaded music, films and software.
In some countries of Europe, less then 10 percent of the population ever pays for the content that is loaded to their computers, smartphones and tablets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovak Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/post/sharpe_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sharpe_18/</guid>
      <description>You can review the slides here.
 or on Slideshare.
The Slovak Music Industy Report can be downloaded from here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEE Mini Recording Industry Workshop</title>
      <link>/post/cee_mini_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cee_mini_17/</guid>
      <description>I presented my market view and experience with distinguished colleagues from the Baltic states, Central Europe and the Balkan, representatives of WIN and IFPI and the international indie distributor State 51. We had a lively discussion on why emerging markets are emerging so slowly in the new digital music business.
After a decade of decline due to piracy and change in business model, the global music business is steadily growing. However, defying some economic expectation, to growth is stronger in mature markets than in most emerging markets, and most of the global growth came from the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMP Session: Licensing, How To Tackle The Value Gap And A Discussion on Licensing Initiatives</title>
      <link>/post/ceempc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ceempc/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID had the honor to participate in the third panel of CEEMP in Warsaw together with Ben McEwen from ICE; Jules Parker from Spotify and Dominic Houston from Netflix, and Chris Butler from Music Sales, who is also the chairperson of ICMP. Our panel was moderated by Nigel Elderton from peermusic, who is also the new chairperson of PRS in the UK.
Jules from Spotify spoke about their new initiative, Spotify for Publishers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Musician Career Paths</title>
      <link>/post/career_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/career_path/</guid>
      <description>In the 20th century the first career step was to get on stage and create a credible live performance. After several years on the stage musician’s got a recording contract, and usually even later they registered their first composition. The recording stream was the most important revenue source. The making of a record was expensive and offered considerable royalties or advances.
In the 21st century the live music stream is far more important than the recordings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Croatian Music Industry</title>
      <link>/post/2016-04-20_makk15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-04-20_makk15/</guid>
      <description>Daniel Antal presented the preliminary findings of the Croatian music industry research in the International Authors’ and Creators’ Conference (Međunarodna autorska kreativna konferencija, #MAKK2015) in Zagreb on 24 November 2015. The presentation was largely based on analysis of various CEEMID databases.
The Central European music industry, as shown by processing the data of more than 2000 musicians in the region is even more reliant on live performances than the British music industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granting And Policy Evaluation For Musicians In Hungary</title>
      <link>/post/2015-11-12_cstp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-11-12_cstp/</guid>
      <description>The data and intelligence of CEEMID was used in Hungary to create an ex ante evaluation of the new Cseh Tamás Program to support popular music development in Hungary. Our mandate was to create concrete granting proposals that have a high chance of making a change in terms of the later royalty earning capabilities of artists.
In the first phase of the project, we made two workshops with the eight fields development method to understand the challenges and existing working practices that result in a low level of royalties paid out in Hungary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first national Hungarian Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/post/proart_report_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/proart_report_15/</guid>
      <description>The report was compiled with joining data and knowledge from collective management agencies for composer, producer and performer royalties, and market leading companies Sziget (organizer of Sziget festival and many more festivals), WMMD music distribution company, market-leading Schubert Music Publishing and A38, Hungary’s leading music club, together with producer and audience survey data, tax authority data and other government sources.
The report was presented in the Music Hungary Conference in 2015 and became the prototype of further Hungarian and regional reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications for tariff setting</title>
      <link>/post/cisac_goodg_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cisac_goodg_13/</guid>
      <description>You can review the slides below.
  Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications in tariff setting  from Dániel Antal 
Contents: 2. Private copying: blank carriers, technology-driven challenges
 Technological changes coupled with arbitrage opportunities on the Single Market undermine revenue collection in some jurisdictions
 Benchmarking breaks down if race starts to the bottom. You can adjust your tariffs to the neighbor without in-depth analysis as long your neighbor charges the right amount.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>