<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CCI on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/cci/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CCI on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 13:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/cci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Crisis Recovery in the CEE &amp; SEE Creative &amp; Cultural Sectors</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-09-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-04-09-recovery/</guid>
      <description>My presentation provided for the Slovak music industry stakeholders in this dialogue are not made available in a more general form, because the problems in Croatia, Hungary, Poland,  Slovakia, and to a great extent in the broader region including Austria, Slovenia and Czechia are very similar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documenting CEEMID For Open Data Use</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-24-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 13:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-24-documentation/</guid>
      <description>The Central European Music Industry Report 2020 was updated with a technical annex that points out to the new wiki documentation website of CEEMID to make our work more accessible for designing the European Music Observatory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of COVID-19 On Creative &amp; Cultural Industries</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-18-covid19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-18-covid19/</guid>
      <description>I was asked to contribute an article to the COVID-19 economic crisis series of the Hungarian business weekly and portal hgv.hu.  While the article is only available in Hungarian, and behind a paywall, it draws on experiences that are very similar across the CEE region, and in some cases, in most the European Union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESCO Focus Group on CCI Occupations and Skills</title>
      <link>/talk/2020_03_12_esco/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 14:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2020_03_12_esco/</guid>
      <description>I will be participating in the ESCO Focus group on Cultural and Creative Occupations and Skills of the Creative FLIP project.
CEEMID has a large enough answer pool for an empirical clustering of occupations. We are able to perform clustering of job descriptions, earnings, educational levels, and work output (such as films, documentaries, TV programmes, live music performances, music compositions, etc) to empirically create groups with a “set of jobs whose main tasks and duties are characterised by a high degree of similarity” in terms of economic activity and work output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Empirical Approach To Modernizing The Cultural and Creative Occupations and Skills Classifications</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-11-esco/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 12:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-11-esco/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID has a large enough answer pool for an empirical clustering of occupations. We are able to perform clustering of job descriptions, earnings, educational levels, and work output (such as films, documentaries, TV programmes, live music performances, music compositions, etc) to empirically create groups with a “set of jobs whose main tasks and duties are characterised by a high degree of similarity” in terms of economic activity and work output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCS Ecosystems: Evidence-Driven CCI Policy &amp; The Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</guid>
      <description>The Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020 was presented as a case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>