<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>royalties on Antal Dániel, CFA</title>
    <link>/hu/tags/royalties/</link>
    <description>Recent content in royalties on Antal Dániel, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>hu</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 10:16:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/hu/tags/royalties/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Comperative Study On The Music Markets of the CEE Region</title>
      <link>/hu/talk/2019_11_08_nouvelle_prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 10:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/talk/2019_11_08_nouvelle_prague/</guid>
      <description>I am going to present the Czech results from our regional Central European Music Industry Report, and the first version of a comprehensive, national music development program that we started to work on in the organization of SoundCzech with 25 music professionals representing more than 20 stakeholders in the How We Would Like To Work in the Czech Music Industry in 2020 ex ante evaluation workshop.
I would like to provide an opportunity on Nouvelle Prague to give personal feedback to the artists and professionals who gave their personal details in our annual CEEMID Music Professional Survey from Czechia, or anywhere else in the region if they make it to Nouvelle Prague.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panelbeszélgetés az első Közép-európai Zeneipari Jelentésről</title>
      <link>/hu/talk/waves_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/talk/waves_2019/</guid>
      <description>A panelbeszélgetés az első közép-európai jelentés (Ausztria, Bulgária, Csehország, Horvátország, Észtország, Lengyelország, Litvánia, Magyarország, Örményország, Románia, Szerbia, Szlovákia, Szlovénia) Waves Music Showcase Fesztviál és Konferencia keretében.
Az alábbiak a konferencia programjában szerepelnek, amit fordítás nélkül teszek közzé.
CEEMID – Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Databases was created out of necessity: many Central and Eastern European countries are lacking effective cross-industry or governmental statistics on music or on cultural industries in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMPC session: Licensing, How To Tackle The Value Gap And A Discussion On Licensing Initiatives</title>
      <link>/hu/talk/ceempc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/talk/ceempc/</guid>
      <description>More information in the blogpost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royalties</title>
      <link>/hu/project/royalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/project/royalties/</guid>
      <description>Royalites are &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the Hungarian Private Copy Remuneration Scheme</title>
      <link>/hu/publication/pcr_hungary_2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hu/publication/pcr_hungary_2013/</guid>
      <description>The original title in Hungarian is Az üreshordozó díjrendszer vizsgálata.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>