<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hungary on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/hungary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hungary on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 18:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/hungary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of COVID-19 On Creative &amp; Cultural Industries</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-18-covid19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-18-covid19/</guid>
      <description>I was asked to contribute an article to the COVID-19 economic crisis series of the Hungarian business weekly and portal hgv.hu. While the article is only available in Hungarian, and behind a paywall, it draws on experiences that are very similar across the CEE region, and in some cases, in most the European Union. (If you undersand the language, click to the Hungarian version of this post.)
LinkedIn version in Hungarian</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCS Ecosystems: Evidence-Driven CCI Policy &amp; The Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent presented and discussed with stakeholders the Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020 as a case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector on the CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.
My presentation was focused around the question on invisibility of the CCI sector in the economic, education and labour policymaking, and the low level of data use in fact-based cultural policy design, and the following policy design problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020</title>
      <link>/publication/ceereport_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ceereport_2020/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent presented and discussed with stakeholders the Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020 as a case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector on the CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.
The CEE Report builds on the results of the first Hungarian, Slovak, Croatian and Czech music industry reports are compared with Armenian, Austrian, Bulgarian, Lithuanian, Serbian and Slovenian data and findings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budapest Showcase Hub &amp; Conference 2019</title>
      <link>/post/2019-11-18-bush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-11-18-bush/</guid>
      <description>We had a very interesting discussion day on the Budapest Showcase Hub with the regional independent labels in the workshop hosted by HAIL and with some concert promoters and music educators in the main conference program.
You can find the full presentation, including slides not shown in the workshop here. The presentation is a self-contained big file of 11Mb, takes time to load.
And here you can review the recordings of the great bands and performers who participated in the showcase festival:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Music Industry 2019</title>
      <link>/talk/2019_11_19_mokk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 10:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019_11_19_mokk/</guid>
      <description>Reading list for students:
Antal Dániel, 2015. “A Proart zeneipari jelentése. [The Music Industry Report of Proart].” ProArt Szövetség a Szerzői Jogokért Egyesület. http://zeneipar.info/letoltes/proart-zeneipari-jelentes-2015.pdf.
Directive (EU) 2019&amp;frasl;790 of the European Parliament and the Council of 17 April 2019 on Copyright and Related Rights in the Digital Single Market and Amending Directives 96/9/EC and 2001/29/EC. 2019. Official Journal of the European Union. https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32019L0790&amp;amp;from=EN.
EYGM. 2014. “Creating Growth – Measuring Cultural and Creative Industries in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hungarian Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/</guid>
      <description>A ProArt zeneipari jelentése  from Dániel Antal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AmCham Energy and Environment Committee published Position Brief</title>
      <link>/publication/amchan_energy_2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/amchan_energy_2010/</guid>
      <description>More detail can easily be written here using Markdown and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the Hungarian Private Copy Remuneration Scheme</title>
      <link>/publication/pcr_hungary_2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pcr_hungary_2013/</guid>
      <description>The original title in Hungarian is Az üreshordozó díjrendszer vizsgálata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market size of the re-usable public sector information in Hungary</title>
      <link>/publication/hungary_psi_2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hungary_psi_2009/</guid>
      <description>Original title in Hungarian: - A közintézmények újrahasznosítható információinak piaca Magyarországon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opportunities for branch lines in the new European regulatory environment</title>
      <link>/publication/hu_branch_lines_2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hu_branch_lines_2004/</guid>
      <description>Original title in Hungarian: A mellékvonalak lehetőségei az új európai vasútszabályozási környezetben, in: Közlekedéstudományi Szemle</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the first year of the liberalized rail freight market for re-regulation</title>
      <link>/publication/hu_rail_transport_2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hu_rail_transport_2004/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>