<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music-industry on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/music-industry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music-industry on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/music-industry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CCS Ecosystems: Evidence-Driven CCI Policy &amp; The Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent presented and discussed with stakeholders the Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020 as a case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector on the CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.
My presentation was focused around the question on invisibility of the CCI sector in the economic, education and labour policymaking, and the low level of data use in fact-based cultural policy design, and the following policy design problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020</title>
      <link>/publication/ceereport_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ceereport_2020/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent presented and discussed with stakeholders the Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020 as a case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector on the CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.
The CEE Report builds on the results of the first Hungarian, Slovak, Croatian and Czech music industry reports are compared with Armenian, Austrian, Bulgarian, Lithuanian, Serbian and Slovenian data and findings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central European Music Industry Report 2020</title>
      <link>/talk/2020_01_29_flip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 14:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2020_01_29_flip/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent will present to the audience the Central European Music Industry Report 2020 (will be availale in all formats on the presentation day) on the CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.
Creative FLIP stands for Finance, Learning, Innovation and Patenting is a Pilot project co-funded by the EU whose main objective is to support healthy and sustainable ecosystems for Cultural and Creative Industries (CCIs) with respect to these four key policy areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budapest Showcase Hub &amp; Conference 2019</title>
      <link>/post/2019-11-18-bush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-11-18-bush/</guid>
      <description>We had a very interesting discussion day on the Budapest Showcase Hub with the regional independent labels in the workshop hosted by HAIL and with some concert promoters and music educators in the main conference program.
You can find the full presentation, including slides not shown in the workshop here. The presentation is a self-contained big file of 11Mb, takes time to load.
And here you can review the recordings of the great bands and performers who participated in the showcase festival:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Music Industry 2019</title>
      <link>/talk/2019_11_19_mokk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 10:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019_11_19_mokk/</guid>
      <description>Reading list for students:
Antal Dániel, 2015. “A Proart zeneipari jelentése. [The Music Industry Report of Proart].” ProArt Szövetség a Szerzői Jogokért Egyesület. http://zeneipar.info/letoltes/proart-zeneipari-jelentes-2015.pdf.
Directive (EU) 2019&amp;frasl;790 of the European Parliament and the Council of 17 April 2019 on Copyright and Related Rights in the Digital Single Market and Amending Directives 96/9/EC and 2001/29/EC. 2019. Official Journal of the European Union. https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32019L0790&amp;amp;from=EN.
EYGM. 2014. “Creating Growth – Measuring Cultural and Creative Industries in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Czech Music Development Program &amp; Comparative Market Research</title>
      <link>/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</guid>
      <description>I was presenting some highlights from the work we started with in the organization of SoundCzech with 25 music professionals representing more than 20 stakeholders in the How We Would Like To Work in the Czech Music Industry in 2020 ex ante evaluation workshop in the context of the comparative Central European Music Industry Report.
You can find the full presentation, including slides not shown in the workshop here. The presentation is a self-contained big file of 20Mb, takes time to load.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying in Croatia</title>
      <link>/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</guid>
      <description>After much delay, the first measurement of licensed use of music, audiovisual content, home copying and value transfer to media platforms in Croatia for a practical update of the private copying remuneration in the country.
You can find the whole study in English, a Croatian language summary and a press release in the Publications section.
The models presented are simplified models of the Hungarian and Slovak models, with less detailed data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central European Music Industry Report Presentation</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 08:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/</guid>
      <description>We had the first public and panel discussion of the forthcoming Central European Music Industry Report. After mapping and analysing in depth the music industries of several CEE countries, I put together with the help of Consolidated Independent and state51 a regional report in previously unseen detail.
You can review the whole presentation here (10Mb self-contained HTML file, takes some time to load).
After mapping and analysing (see most recently Slovakia) in depth the music industries of several CEE countries, with the help of Consolidated Independent I put together a regional report in previously unseen detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Market Growth on European Markets</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-24_index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-24_index/</guid>
      <description>I have never been a great fan of the headline figures reported by the recording industry about streaming growth. I always felt that however dynamic are those charts, artists keep complaining that they do not feel these developments. So I started to decompose those growth figures.
The Global Music Report quotes national streaming revenues on a dollar basis, which contains a lot of currency exchange noise. And behind the national total there are too many factors: subscriber base growth and repertoire growth and the subscription fee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Market Shares on Spotify Hitlists</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</guid>
      <description>If we take a look at the streaming charts of the region, we usually find that the vast majority of the streamed songs are foreign songs - except for Austria, U.S. songs. For comparison, we added a similar, middle-income emerging market (Argentina) and a rich, small-population English-speaking country, Australia to the chart. These countries seem to be in a similar position to the CEE countries.
Arguably, the strongest countries of songwriting are the United States and Brazil - these are the countries that have ran out of the ISRC recording identifier range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovak Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/</guid>
      <description>The whole report can be downloaded for free from the homepage of SOZA.
Press reports in Slovak:
SME: SOZA predstavila prvú Správu o slovenskom hudobnom priemysle
Kreatívna Europa: Historicky prvá Správa o slovenskom hudobnom priemysle prináša okrem analýz aj odporúčania pre budúcnosť
In Hungarian: Új Szó: Tudományosan a hazai zeneiparról
Slides:
  Spáva o hudobnom priemysle na Slovensku  from Dániel Antal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eurpoean Comparison: How Many People Ever Pay For Music, Film or Software</title>
      <link>/post/how_many_ever_pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how_many_ever_pay/</guid>
      <description>In our recent private copying reports we compiled European survey data relevant to analysis. In Europe, there is a big difference between the use of electronic entertainment devices in richer and poorer countries. Nevertheless, the real difference is between the number of people who sometimes and who never pay for downloaded music, films and software.
In some countries of Europe, less then 10 percent of the population ever pays for the content that is loaded to their computers, smartphones and tablets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovak Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/post/sharpe_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sharpe_18/</guid>
      <description>You can review the slides here.
 or on Slideshare.
The Slovak Music Industy Report can be downloaded from here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEE Mini Recording Industry Workshop</title>
      <link>/post/cee_mini_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cee_mini_17/</guid>
      <description>I presented my market view and experience with distinguished colleagues from the Baltic states, Central Europe and the Balkan, representatives of WIN and IFPI and the international indie distributor State 51. We had a lively discussion on why emerging markets are emerging so slowly in the new digital music business.
After a decade of decline due to piracy and change in business model, the global music business is steadily growing. However, defying some economic expectation, to growth is stronger in mature markets than in most emerging markets, and most of the global growth came from the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Musician Career Paths</title>
      <link>/post/career_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/career_path/</guid>
      <description>In the 20th century the first career step was to get on stage and create a credible live performance. After several years on the stage musician’s got a recording contract, and usually even later they registered their first composition. The recording stream was the most important revenue source. The making of a record was expensive and offered considerable royalties or advances.
In the 21st century the live music stream is far more important than the recordings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Growth of the Hungarian Popular Music Repertoire: Who Creates It And How Does It Find An Audience</title>
      <link>/publication/made_in_hungary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/made_in_hungary/</guid>
      <description>Being visible in the world is always difficult in the Central and Eastern European region. Made in Hungary is the first book in the Popular Music Studies series of Routledge from the region. A description of our first datasets, the motivation of the research and the CEEMID concept is laid out as a closing, quantitative chapter in the book.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Croatian Music Industry</title>
      <link>/post/2016-04-20_makk15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-04-20_makk15/</guid>
      <description>Daniel Antal presented the preliminary findings of the Croatian music industry research in the International Authors’ and Creators’ Conference (Međunarodna autorska kreativna konferencija, #MAKK2015) in Zagreb on 24 November 2015. The presentation was largely based on analysis of various CEEMID databases.
The Central European music industry, as shown by processing the data of more than 2000 musicians in the region is even more reliant on live performances than the British music industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hungarian Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/</guid>
      <description>A ProArt zeneipari jelentése  from Dániel Antal</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>