<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music-industry on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/music-industry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music-industry on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/music-industry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CCS Ecosystems: Evidence-Driven CCI Policy &amp; The Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/</guid>
      <description>The Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020 was presented as a case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central &amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020</title>
      <link>/publication/ceereport_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ceereport_2020/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent presented and discussed with stakeholders the Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020 as a case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector on the CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.
The CEE Report builds on the results of the first Hungarian, Slovak, Croatian and Czech music industry reports are compared with Armenian, Austrian, Bulgarian, Lithuanian, Serbian and Slovenian data and findings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central European Music Industry Report 2020</title>
      <link>/talk/2020_01_29_flip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 14:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2020_01_29_flip/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent will present to the audience the Central European Music Industry Report 2020 (will be availale in all formats on the presentation day) on the CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.
Creative FLIP stands for Finance, Learning, Innovation and Patenting is a Pilot project co-funded by the EU whose main objective is to support healthy and sustainable ecosystems for Cultural and Creative Industries (CCIs) with respect to these four key policy areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budapest Showcase Hub &amp; Conference 2019</title>
      <link>/post/2019-11-18-bush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-11-18-bush/</guid>
      <description>We had a very interesting discussion day on the Budapest Showcase Hub with the regional independent labels in the workshop hosted by HAIL and with some concert promoters and music educators in the main conference program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Music Industry 2019</title>
      <link>/talk/2019_11_19_mokk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 10:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019_11_19_mokk/</guid>
      <description>Reading list for students:
Antal Dániel, 2015. “A Proart zeneipari jelentése. [The Music Industry Report of Proart].” ProArt Szövetség a Szerzői Jogokért Egyesület. http://zeneipar.info/letoltes/proart-zeneipari-jelentes-2015.pdf.
Directive (EU) 2019&amp;frasl;790 of the European Parliament and the Council of 17 April 2019 on Copyright and Related Rights in the Digital Single Market and Amending Directives 96/9/EC and 2001/29/EC. 2019. Official Journal of the European Union. https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32019L0790&amp;amp;from=EN.
EYGM. 2014. “Creating Growth – Measuring Cultural and Creative Industries in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Czech Music Development Program &amp; Comparative Market Research</title>
      <link>/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</guid>
      <description>A Progress Report on the Czech Music Development Program and problems in an international context. We would like to invite any Czech stakeholders, or even individuals to join our Research Consortium, because in the music sector, all organization are microenterprise or small enterprise sized, they usually have no significant market research, innovation and strategic HR management capacities. We hope to give them in each country useful tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying in Croatia</title>
      <link>/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</guid>
      <description>My study, Private Copying in Croatia, argues for an overhaul of the Croatian private copying remuneration scheme and gives some empirical evidence for the transposition of the DSM Directive. Even for those who are not interested in royalties, the first 3 chapters offer a very interesting introduction on how people listen to music, how musicians make music and how people copy it in the 21st century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central European Music Industry Report Presentation</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 08:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-27_cee_report/</guid>
      <description>We had the first public and panel discussion of the forthcoming Central European Music Industry Report.  After mapping and analysing in depth the music industries of several CEE countries, I put together with the help of Consolidated Independent and state51 a regional report in previously unseen detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Market Growth on European Markets</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-24_index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-24_index/</guid>
      <description>Total national sales reflect the growing number of subscribers, the price, the exchange rate, and many factors that are not important for an artists or music label. Instead we design indexes that show the real growth for a typical domestic or foreign rightsholder in a country.  The aim is to provide useful sales and performance guidance for smaller countries, genres and exporting destinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Market Shares on Spotify Hitlists</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</guid>
      <description>Which are the European countries that can successfully export songs on a streaming platform? What are the differences in cross-border hits from the UK, France, Germany, the Netherlands and Sweden?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovak Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/slovak_music_industry_2019/</guid>
      <description>The whole report can be downloaded for free from the homepage of SOZA.
Press reports in Slovak:
SME: SOZA predstavila prvú Správu o slovenskom hudobnom priemysle
Kreatívna Europa: Historicky prvá Správa o slovenskom hudobnom priemysle prináša okrem analýz aj odporúčania pre budúcnosť
In Hungarian: Új Szó: Tudományosan a hazai zeneiparról
Slides:
  Spáva o hudobnom priemysle na Slovensku  from Dániel Antal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eurpoean Comparison: How Many People Ever Pay For Music, Film or Software</title>
      <link>/post/how_many_ever_pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how_many_ever_pay/</guid>
      <description>In Europe, there is a big difference between the use of electronic entertainment devices in richer and poorer countries. Nevertheless, the real difference is between the number of people who sometimes and who never pay for downloaded music, films and software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovak Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/post/sharpe_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sharpe_18/</guid>
      <description>We presented the most important findings of the Slovak Music Industry Report with the project sponsor, Mgr. Tomas Miks, member of SOZA’s management team in the first SHARPE music conference in Bratislava.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEE Mini Recording Industry Workshop</title>
      <link>/post/cee_mini_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cee_mini_17/</guid>
      <description>I presented my market view and experience with distinguished colleagues from the Baltic states, Central Europe and the Balkan, representatives of WIN and IFPI and the international indie distributor State 51. We had a lively discussion on why emerging markets are emerging so slowly in the new digital music business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Musician Career Paths</title>
      <link>/post/career_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/career_path/</guid>
      <description>In our survey, we ask musicians about the most important milestones of their career and their achievement in the past 12 month. So far we have surveyed more than 2000 music professionals and 900 film production professionals in Croatia, Hungary and Slovakia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Growth of the Hungarian Popular Music Repertoire: Who Creates It And How Does It Find An Audience</title>
      <link>/publication/made_in_hungary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/made_in_hungary/</guid>
      <description>Being visible in the world is always difficult in the Central and Eastern European region. Made in Hungary is the first book in the Popular Music Studies series of Routledge from the region. A description of our first datasets, the motivation of the research and the CEEMID concept is laid out as a closing, quantitative chapter in the book.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Croatian Music Industry</title>
      <link>/post/2016-04-20_makk15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-04-20_makk15/</guid>
      <description>Daniel Antal presented the preliminary findings of the Croatian music industry research in the International Authors’ and Creators’ Conference in Zagreb on 24 November 2015. The presentation was largely based on analysis of various CEEMID databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hungarian Music Industry Report</title>
      <link>/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hungary_music_industry_2014/</guid>
      <description>A ProArt zeneipari jelentése  from Dániel Antal</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>