<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>royalties on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/royalties/</link>
    <description>Recent content in royalties on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:16:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/royalties/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Panel Discussion of the Central Euroepan Music Industry Report 2019</title>
      <link>/talk/waves_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/waves_2019/</guid>
      <description>The panel discussion of the first comprehensive Central and Eastern European report (Albania, Armenia, Austria, Bulgaria, Croatia, Czechia, Estonia, Lithuania, Poland, Romania, Slovakia, Slovenia) will be in held on the Waves Music Showcase Festival and Conference.
You can read a related blogpost here.
Quoted from the conference agenda:
CEEMID – Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Databases was created out of necessity: many Central and Eastern European countries are lacking effective cross-industry or governmental statistics on music or on cultural industries in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMPC session: Licensing, How To Tackle The Value Gap And A Discussion On Licensing Initiatives</title>
      <link>/talk/ceempc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/ceempc/</guid>
      <description>More information in the blogpost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royalties</title>
      <link>/project/royalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/royalties/</guid>
      <description>Valuing music, film, and projecting royalty flows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royalties</title>
      <link>/project/royalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/royalties/</guid>
      <description>Valuing music, film, and projecting royalty flows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granting And Policy Evaluation For Musicians In Hungary</title>
      <link>/post/cstp_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cstp_15/</guid>
      <description>The data and intelligence of CEEMID was used in Hungary to create an ex ante evaluation of the new Cseh Tamás Program to support popular music development in Hungary.  Our mandate was to create concrete granting proposals that have a high chance of making a change in terms of the later royalty earning capabilities of artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the Hungarian Private Copy Remuneration Scheme</title>
      <link>/publication/pcr_hungary_2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pcr_hungary_2013/</guid>
      <description>The original title in Hungarian is Az üreshordozó díjrendszer vizsgálata.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>