<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>value-gap on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/value-gap/</link>
    <description>Recent content in value-gap on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 10:18:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/value-gap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenges for Independent Labels in 2020</title>
      <link>/talk/2019_11_14_hail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 10:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019_11_14_hail/</guid>
      <description>I am going to present the Hungarian results from our regional Central European Music Industry Report, and reflect on current challenges with promoting music in digital streaming and changes due to the new DSM directive. We will discuss some projects, including market development projects for the non-EU Balkans countries.
I would like to provide an opportunity on BUSH to give personal feedback to the artists and professionals who gave their personal details in our annual CEEMID Music Professional Survey from Hungary, or anywhere else in the region if they make it to BUSH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Czech Music Development Program &amp; Comparative Market Research</title>
      <link>/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-11-09-nouvelle-prague/</guid>
      <description>A Progress Report on the Czech Music Development Program and problems in an international context. We would like to invite any Czech stakeholders, or even individuals to join our Research Consortium, because in the music sector, all organization are microenterprise or small enterprise sized, they usually have no significant market research, innovation and strategic HR management capacities. We hope to give them in each country useful tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying in Croatia</title>
      <link>/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-10-31-croatia_pcr/</guid>
      <description>My study, Private Copying in Croatia, argues for an overhaul of the Croatian private copying remuneration scheme and gives some empirical evidence for the transposition of the DSM Directive. Even for those who are not interested in royalties, the first 3 chapters offer a very interesting introduction on how people listen to music, how musicians make music and how people copy it in the 21st century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying in Croatia</title>
      <link>/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/</guid>
      <description>Press release: Studija: Naknade za privatno kopiranje (BTL) u Hrvatskoj drastično ispod prosjeka EU
Short summary in Croatian: Privatno kopiranje u Hrvatskoj Full text in English: Private Copying in Croatia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSM Directive, Value Gap &amp; Private Copying Levies</title>
      <link>/post/dsm_pcr_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dsm_pcr_19/</guid>
      <description>We see common threats and common opportunities with the national implementations of the DSM Directive.  While it is not addressing private copying, it is aiming to re-arrange the power balance between users and rightsholders of certain unlicensed, or not fully-licensed and compensated uses. Users will use this opportunity to keep as much as possible from the value transfer to their media platforms, and hardware manufacturers will try to freeze very low private copying remuneration levels in the region. Or worse still: to reduce them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMP Session: Licensing, How To Tackle The Value Gap And A Discussion on Licensing Initiatives</title>
      <link>/post/ceempc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ceempc/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID had the honor to participate in the third panel of CEEMP in Warsaw together with Ben McEwen from ICE; Jules Parker from Spotify and Dominic Houston from Netflix, and Chris Butler from Music Sales, who is also the chairperson of ICMP. Our panel was moderated by Nigel Elderton from peermusic, who is also the new chairperson of PRS in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing</title>
      <link>/project/pricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pricing/</guid>
      <description>Optimize pricing or review regulated prices</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>