<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>value-gap on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/value-gap/</link>
    <description>Recent content in value-gap on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/value-gap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copying in Croatia</title>
      <link>/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/private_copying_croatia_2019/</guid>
      <description>Press release: Studija: Naknade za privatno kopiranje (BTL) u Hrvatskoj drastično ispod prosjeka EU
Short summary in Croatian: Privatno kopiranje u Hrvatskoj Full text in English: Private Copying in Croatia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSM Directive, Value Gap &amp; Private Copying Levies</title>
      <link>/post/dsm_pcr_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dsm_pcr_19/</guid>
      <description>We see common threats and common opportunities with the national implementations of the DSM Directive.  While it is not addressing private copying, it is aiming to re-arrange the power balance between users and rightsholders of certain unlicensed, or not fully-licensed and compensated uses. Users will use this opportunity to keep as much as possible from the value transfer to their media platforms, and hardware manufacturers will try to freeze very low private copying remuneration levels in the region. Or worse still: to reduce them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMP Session: Licensing, How To Tackle The Value Gap And A Discussion on Licensing Initiatives</title>
      <link>/post/ceempc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ceempc/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID had the honor to participate in the third panel of CEEMP in Warsaw together with Ben McEwen from ICE; Jules Parker from Spotify and Dominic Houston from Netflix, and Chris Butler from Music Sales, who is also the chairperson of ICMP. Our panel was moderated by Nigel Elderton from peermusic, who is also the new chairperson of PRS in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing</title>
      <link>/project/pricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pricing/</guid>
      <description>Optimize pricing or review regulated prices</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>