<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hitlists on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/hitlists/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hitlists on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 19:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/hitlists/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Market Growth on European Markets</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-24_index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-24_index/</guid>
      <description>I have never been a great fan of the headline figures reported by the recording industry about streaming growth. I always felt that however dynamic are those charts, artists keep complaining that they do not feel these developments. So I started to decompose those growth figures.
The Global Music Report quotes national streaming revenues on a dollar basis, which contains a lot of currency exchange noise. And behind the national total there are too many factors: subscriber base growth and repertoire growth and the subscription fee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Market Shares on Spotify Hitlists</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-23_cross-border_europe/</guid>
      <description>If we take a look at the streaming charts of the region, we usually find that the vast majority of the streamed songs are foreign songs - except for Austria, U.S. songs. For comparison, we added a similar, middle-income emerging market (Argentina) and a rich, small-population English-speaking country, Australia to the chart. These countries seem to be in a similar position to the CEE countries.
Arguably, the strongest countries of songwriting are the United States and Brazil - these are the countries that have ran out of the ISRC recording identifier range.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>