<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMID</title>
      <link>/project/ceemid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ceemid/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID (Central and Eastern European Music Industry Databases) were created by Consultant Daniel Antal, CFA and three collective management societies in 2014 as a platform to collect, share and integrate data for royalty price setting, economic impact evaluation and taxation on music. The aim was to bring emerging market stakeholders to the information level of mature market stakeholders.
CEEMID uses various forms of data collection. * Nationally representative surveys of music users and film viewers * Anonymous surveys of musicians and filmmakers about their work, incomes and costs * Big data sources from various geolocational applications about events and location visits * Automatic data retrieval from open data sources * Industry data sources such as the CISAC and IFPI global reports, the European Audiovisual Yearbook, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Reports</title>
      <link>/project/market_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/market_report/</guid>
      <description>I have been creating market reports for 20 years, mainly in emerging markets where data is scarce and often has little history.
Starting as a junior consultant, I learned a lot about data acquisition. Later I held a &amp;lsquo;strategic information management&amp;rsquo; position in the Ministry of Economy and Transport in Hungary with oversight on the national statistical data collection. As a senior consultant and a former lecture, I used to train junior colleagues and journalists on data acquisition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R</title>
      <link>/project/r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/r/</guid>
      <description>The symmetric input-output tables (SIOTs) are complex statistical products that present inter-related statistics in a predefined structure. They are often found in spreadsheets that follow this structure, or in the case Eurostat in a data repository. In both cases they in reproducible research must be downloaded and restructured to programmatically accessible form. Often these highly structured statistics need to be analyzed together with other data, for example, when employment effects and multipliers are calculated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grants</title>
      <link>/project/grants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/grants/</guid>
      <description>Governments, the EU, international organizations and private donors often support causes of public interest with grants and donations. In some cases, these grants are aimed to help starting or sustaining economic activities. In other cases, they are supporting artistic activities or education.
I had been involved in the professional assessment of granting schemes and grant applications since 2000. I have learned and taught various assessment methods to evaluated EU and national grants to support valuable public infrastructure, energy savings, health investments and other causes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing</title>
      <link>/project/pricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pricing/</guid>
      <description>At a very early stage of my career I specialized in regulated prices and acquired a second degree in Economic Regulation and Competition Policy. As an advisor to the minister, I set up a regulatory framework with new regulation for Hungarian freight railways. As a regulator or as a consultant to the authority I participated in price reviews. As a consultant to regulated industries, I helped making legally allowed pricing decisions or helped to challenge regulatory decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royalties</title>
      <link>/project/royalties/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/royalties/</guid>
      <description>Royalties are earnings on intellectual properties. In music, they are the earnings of the music composer, the performer and the producer and the recorded performance. Creators of films, books, software, and other artistic works or intellectual products are entitled to various forms of royalties.
Many royalties are collectively managed, like the musicians pay after radio or restaurant plays. Other royalties, like revenues of app developers, are directly or indirectly paid to them by the buyer of their products.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>