<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>open-data on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/open-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in open-data on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/open-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenData</title>
      <link>/project/opendata/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/opendata/</guid>
      <description>I have been involved in various OpenData projects since 2007, shortly after the introduction of the groundbreaking Re-Use of Public Sector Information Directive (last year replaced with the new Open Data Directive) of the Euroepan Union. (A brief history of this important EU policy can be found here and its importance (pdf).)
Press the tag below to see more examples</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My economic impact package, iotables, has a much updated released on CRAN</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-04_iotables_released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-04_iotables_released/</guid>
      <description>This package was related to several of my works for Slovak, Hungarian and Croatian music industry and the Hungarian Film Fund, and my collaboration with Eeconomic impacT s.r.o in the Czech Republic. My R package downloads symmetric input-output and related tax, margins, use tables from the Eurostat bulk data warehouse, and organizes them for macroeconomic analysis.
The analytical functions of the package create the usual economic impact analysis, including direct effects, multipliers on gross value added, employment, CO2 or other factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market size of the re-usable public sector information in Hungary</title>
      <link>/publication/hungary_psi_2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hungary_psi_2009/</guid>
      <description>Original title in Hungarian: - A közintézmények újrahasznosítható információinak piaca Magyarországon</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>