<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>open-data on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/open-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in open-data on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 17:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/open-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First CEEMID Regional Opendata Release</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/</guid>
      <description>In the preparation to make the CEEMID available as an open-source data integration platform and as a source of open data for the European Music Observatory, the first regional dataset was published today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documenting CEEMID For Open Data Use</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-24-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 13:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-24-documentation/</guid>
      <description>The Central European Music Industry Report 2020 was updated with a technical annex that points out to the new wiki documentation website of CEEMID to make our work more accessible for designing the European Music Observatory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenData</title>
      <link>/project/opendata/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/opendata/</guid>
      <description>Market sizing, research and forecasting reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My economic impact package, iotables, has a much updated released on CRAN</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-04_iotables_released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-04_iotables_released/</guid>
      <description>The analytical functions of the package create the usual economic impact analysis, including direct effects, multipliers on gross value added, employment, CO2 or other factors. The package creates a programmatic interface to compare economic impact changes in time, or compare any country with any country in the European Union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating better national cultural statistics with Eurobarometer datasets and ESSNet-Culture technical recommendations</title>
      <link>/publication/creating_better_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/creating_better_2015/</guid>
      <description>You can download the poster presentation here  or you can zoom into it with prezi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market size of the re-usable public sector information in Hungary</title>
      <link>/publication/hungary_psi_2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hungary_psi_2009/</guid>
      <description>A localization of the measuring European Public Sector Information resources for Hungary in the fields of Business information, geographic information, legal information, meteorological information, social data and transport information. Market sizing, service levels, pricing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>