<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Central European Music Industry Report 2020</title>
      <link>/talk/2020_01_29_flip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 14:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2020_01_29_flip/</guid>
      <description>CEEMID &amp;amp; Consolidated Independent will present to the audience the Central European Music Industry Report 2020 on the CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.
Creative FLIP stands for Finance, Learning, Innovation and Patenting is a Pilot project co-funded by the EU whose main objective is to support healthy and sustainable ecosystems for Cultural and Creative Industries (CCIs) with respect to these four key policy areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Music Industry 2019</title>
      <link>/talk/2019_11_19_mokk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 10:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019_11_19_mokk/</guid>
      <description>Reading list for students:
Antal Dániel, 2015. “A Proart zeneipari jelentése. [The Music Industry Report of Proart].” ProArt Szövetség a Szerzői Jogokért Egyesület. http://zeneipar.info/letoltes/proart-zeneipari-jelentes-2015.pdf.
Directive (EU) 2019&amp;frasl;790 of the European Parliament and the Council of 17 April 2019 on Copyright and Related Rights in the Digital Single Market and Amending Directives 96/9/EC and 2001/29/EC. 2019. Official Journal of the European Union. https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32019L0790&amp;amp;from=EN.
EYGM. 2014. “Creating Growth – Measuring Cultural and Creative Industries in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenges for Independent Labels in 2020</title>
      <link>/talk/2019_11_14_hail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 10:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019_11_14_hail/</guid>
      <description>I am going to present the Hungarian results from our regional Central European Music Industry Report, and reflect on current challenges with promoting music in digital streaming and changes due to the new DSM directive. We will discuss some projects, including market development projects for the non-EU Balkans countries.
I would like to provide an opportunity on BUSH to give personal feedback to the artists and professionals who gave their personal details in our annual CEEMID Music Professional Survey from Hungary, or anywhere else in the region if they make it to BUSH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Practical Tools To Plan Better Tours, Record Promotion and Grants. Evidence from 10 countries</title>
      <link>/talk/2019_11_15_bush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 10:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019_11_15_bush/</guid>
      <description>I am going to look back on the needs assessment of Hungarian music professionals in 2015 and Czechs in 2019.I will also compare the problems of the Hungarian scene in 2015, 2019 with the current issues in Czechia, Slovakia and Austria.
I would like to provide an opportunity on BUSH to give personal feedback to the artists and professionals who gave their personal details in our annual CEEMID Music Professional Survey from Hungary, or anywhere else in the region if they make it to BUSH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comperative Study On The Music Markets of the CEE Region</title>
      <link>/talk/2019_11_08_nouvelle_prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 10:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019_11_08_nouvelle_prague/</guid>
      <description>I am going to present the Czech results from our regional Central European Music Industry Report, and the first version of a comprehensive, national music development program that we started to work on in the organization of SoundCzech with 25 music professionals representing more than 20 stakeholders in the How We Would Like To Work in the Czech Music Industry in 2020 ex ante evaluation workshop.
I would like to provide an opportunity on Nouvelle Prague to give personal feedback to the artists and professionals who gave their personal details in our annual CEEMID Music Professional Survey from Czechia, or anywhere else in the region if they make it to Nouvelle Prague.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Would Like To Work in the Czech Music Industry in 2020</title>
      <link>/talk/2019_10_09_praha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 10:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019_10_09_praha/</guid>
      <description>This is a similar event to Granting And Policy Evaluation For Musicians In Hungary and it is by invitation only. If you would like to participate and you can commit 8 hours to this event, please get in touch with me.
I am available for a short meeting outside the event in Prague the day after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panel Discussion of the Central Euroepan Music Industry Report 2019</title>
      <link>/talk/waves_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 10:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/waves_2019/</guid>
      <description>The panel discussion of the first comprehensive Central and Eastern European report (Albania, Armenia, Austria, Bulgaria, Croatia, Czechia, Estonia, Lithuania, Poland, Romania, Slovakia, Slovenia) will be in held on the Waves Music Showcase Festival and Conference.
The presentation 10Mb self-contained HTML file, takes some time to load
You can read a related blogpost here
Quoted from the conference agenda:
CEEMID – Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Databases was created out of necessity: many Central and Eastern European countries are lacking effective cross-industry or governmental statistics on music or on cultural industries in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IMPALA CEE Workshop 2019</title>
      <link>/talk/impala_cee_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/impala_cee_2019/</guid>
      <description>IMPALA CEE 2019 Workshop  from Dániel Antal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation of the Slovak Music Industry Report 2019</title>
      <link>/talk/slovak_report19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/slovak_report19/</guid>
      <description>The venue is V klub, Národné Osvetové Centrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMPC session: Licensing, How To Tackle The Value Gap And A Discussion On Licensing Initiatives</title>
      <link>/talk/ceempc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/ceempc/</guid>
      <description>More information in the blogpost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAKK2015 International authors’ and creators’ conference</title>
      <link>/talk/makk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/makk/</guid>
      <description>Collecting and analyzing industry data is very important for small, national music industries that do not have a large enough repertoire that can be easily promoted on global platforms such as Spotify, Deezer or YouTube. New digital platforms produce relatively low income for Central and Southeastern European artists and labels, but they are growing at a rate similar to mature markets with a short, 1-5 years lag. Understanding the different strategies of global service providers, forthcoming liberalization and data-driven analytics are very important to maintain the share of domestic music in the radio and television channels and further expand it in the new channels.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>