<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pricing on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/pricing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pricing on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/pricing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CEE Mini Recording Industry Workshop</title>
      <link>/post/cee_mini_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cee_mini_17/</guid>
      <description>I presented my market view and experience with distinguished colleagues from the Baltic states, Central Europe and the Balkan, representatives of WIN and IFPI and the international indie distributor State 51. We had a lively discussion on why emerging markets are emerging so slowly in the new digital music business.
After a decade of decline due to piracy and change in business model, the global music business is steadily growing. However, defying some economic expectation, to growth is stronger in mature markets than in most emerging markets, and most of the global growth came from the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications for tariff setting</title>
      <link>/talk/ceemp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/ceemp/</guid>
      <description>You can review the slides here.
  Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications in tariff setting  from Dániel Antal 
Contents: 2. 2 Private copying: blank carriers, technology-driven challenges 3. 3 Technological changes coupled with arbitrage opportunities on the Single Market undermine revenue collection in some jurisdictions 4. Benchmarking breaks down if race starts to the bottom. You can adjust your tariffs to the neighbor without in-depth analysis as long your neighbor charges the right amount.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market size of the re-usable public sector information in Hungary</title>
      <link>/publication/hungary_psi_2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hungary_psi_2009/</guid>
      <description>Original title in Hungarian: - A közintézmények újrahasznosítható információinak piaca Magyarországon</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>