<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pricing on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/pricing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pricing on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 17:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/pricing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DSM Directive, Value Gap &amp; Private Copying Levies</title>
      <link>/post/dsm_pcr_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dsm_pcr_19/</guid>
      <description>Private copying after 60 years remains a very important way of spreading recorded music, books and audiovisual works, and a very important source of revenue for artists, composers, writers, film writers and performers if managed properly. According to our research, the value of private copying is far bigger these days than when most CEE private copying remuneration mechanisms were set up.
While the new DSM Directive
We see common threats and common opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEE Mini Recording Industry Workshop</title>
      <link>/post/cee_mini_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cee_mini_17/</guid>
      <description>I presented my market view and experience with distinguished colleagues from the Baltic states, Central Europe and the Balkan, representatives of WIN and IFPI and the international indie distributor State 51. We had a lively discussion on why emerging markets are emerging so slowly in the new digital music business.
After a decade of decline due to piracy and change in business model, the global music business is steadily growing. However, defying some economic expectation, to growth is stronger in mature markets than in most emerging markets, and most of the global growth came from the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEMPC session: Licensing, How To Tackle The Value Gap And A Discussion On Licensing Initiatives</title>
      <link>/talk/ceempc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/ceempc/</guid>
      <description>More information in the blogpost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing</title>
      <link>/project/pricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pricing/</guid>
      <description>At a very early stage of my career I specialized in regulated prices and acquired a second degree in Economic Regulation and Competition Policy. As an advisor to the minister, I set up a regulatory framework with new regulation for Hungarian freight railways. As a regulator or as a consultant to the authority I participated in price reviews. As a consultant to regulated industries, I helped making legally allowed pricing decisions or helped to challenge regulatory decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications for tariff setting</title>
      <link>/post/cisac_goodg_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cisac_goodg_13/</guid>
      <description>You can review the slides below.
  Value added by music in public performance and home copying: economic theory and empirical applications in tariff setting  from Dániel Antal 
Contents: 2. Private copying: blank carriers, technology-driven challenges
 Technological changes coupled with arbitrage opportunities on the Single Market undermine revenue collection in some jurisdictions
 Benchmarking breaks down if race starts to the bottom. You can adjust your tariffs to the neighbor without in-depth analysis as long your neighbor charges the right amount.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market size of the re-usable public sector information in Hungary</title>
      <link>/publication/hungary_psi_2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hungary_psi_2009/</guid>
      <description>Original title in Hungarian: - A közintézmények újrahasznosítható információinak piaca Magyarországon</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>