<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grants on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/grants/</link>
    <description>Recent content in grants on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 10:16:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/grants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Practical Tools To Plan Better Tours, Record Promotion and Grants. Evidence from 10 countries</title>
      <link>/talk/2019_11_15_bush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 10:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019_11_15_bush/</guid>
      <description>I am going to look back on the needs assessment of Hungarian music professionals in 2015 and Czechs in 2019.I will also compare the problems of the Hungarian scene in 2015, 2019 with the current issues in Czechia, Slovakia and Austria.
I would like to provide an opportunity on BUSH to give personal feedback to the artists and professionals who gave their personal details in our annual CEEMID Music Professional Survey from Hungary, or anywhere else in the region if they make it to BUSH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comperative Study On The Music Markets of the CEE Region</title>
      <link>/talk/2019_11_08_nouvelle_prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 10:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019_11_08_nouvelle_prague/</guid>
      <description>I am going to present the Czech results from our regional Central European Music Industry Report, and the first version of a comprehensive, national music development program that we started to work on in the organization of SoundCzech with 25 music professionals representing more than 20 stakeholders in the How We Would Like To Work in the Czech Music Industry in 2020 ex ante evaluation workshop.
I would like to provide an opportunity on Nouvelle Prague to give personal feedback to the artists and professionals who gave their personal details in our annual CEEMID Music Professional Survey from Czechia, or anywhere else in the region if they make it to Nouvelle Prague.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Would Like To Work in the Czech Music Industry in 2020</title>
      <link>/talk/2019_10_09_praha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 10:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019_10_09_praha/</guid>
      <description>This is a similar event to Granting And Policy Evaluation For Musicians In Hungary and it is by invitation only. If you would like to participate and you can commit 8 hours to this event, please get in touch with me.
I am available for a short meeting outside the event in Prague the day after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grants</title>
      <link>/project/grants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/grants/</guid>
      <description>Governments, the EU, international organizations and private donors often support causes of public interest with grants and donations. In some cases, these grants are aimed to help starting or sustaining economic activities. In other cases, they are supporting artistic activities or education.
I had been involved in the professional assessment of granting schemes and grant applications since 2000. I have learned and taught various assessment methods to evaluated EU and national grants to support valuable public infrastructure, energy savings, health investments and other causes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granting And Policy Evaluation For Musicians In Hungary</title>
      <link>/post/2015-11-12_cstp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-11-12_cstp/</guid>
      <description>The data and intelligence of CEEMID was used in Hungary to create an ex ante evaluation of the new Cseh Tamás Program to support popular music development in Hungary. Our mandate was to create concrete granting proposals that have a high chance of making a change in terms of the later royalty earning capabilities of artists.
In the first phase of the project, we made two workshops with the eight fields development method to understand the challenges and existing working practices that result in a low level of royalties paid out in Hungary.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>