<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grants on Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
    <link>/tags/grants/</link>
    <description>Recent content in grants on Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - &amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/grants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Grants</title>
      <link>/project/grants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/grants/</guid>
      <description>Governments, the EU, international organizations and private donors often support causes of public interest with grants and donations. In some cases, these grants are aimed to help starting or sustaining economic activities. In other cases, they are supporting artistic activities or education.
I had been involved in the professional assessment of granting schemes and grant applications since 2000. I have learned and taught various assessment methods to evaluated EU and national grants to support valuable public infrastructure, energy savings, health investments and other causes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granting And Policy Evaluation For Musicians In Hungary</title>
      <link>/post/cstp_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cstp_15/</guid>
      <description>The data and intelligence of CEEMID was used in Hungary to create an ex ante evaluation of the new Cseh Tamás Program to support popular music development in Hungary. Our mandate was to create concrete granting proposals that have a high chance of making a change in terms of the later royalty earning capabilities of artists.
In the first phase of the project, we made two workshops with the eight fields development method to understand the challenges and existing working practices that result in a low level of royalties paid out in Hungary.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>